<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Elasticsearch]]></title><description><![CDATA[Open Source Distributed Real Time Search & Analytics]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 12:09:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 12:09:28 GMT</pubDate><language><![CDATA[en-us]]></language><item><title><![CDATA[Writing Metricbeat modules based on other modules: Introducing light modules]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Metricbeat has modules that support the collection of metrics using specific protocols in a generic way, allowing you to leverage the Elastic Stack for fetching, storing, and analyzing information coming from other existing solutions. These generic modules also provide a way of extending Metricbeat functionality by monitoring services that don’t have their own native modules. Some examples are the modules for<a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-prometheus.html"> Prometheus</a>, <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-jolokia.html">Jolokia</a>, and <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-aws-cloudwatch.html">AWS cloudwatch</a>.
</p><p>Internally, we sometimes call these modules “input” 
modules, because of the parallelism we find between them and Filebeat 
inputs. 
	<a href="/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.3/configuration-filebeat-options.html">Filebeat inputs</a> can be used on their own, but they are also the foundations of <a href="/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.3/filebeat-modules-overview.html">Filebeat modules</a>. Filebeat modules can be seen as packaged Filebeat configurations that cover specific services or use cases. They work by collecting 
information using inputs, but also include documentation, field mappings, and dashboards, extending filebeat functionality without Go code. We wondered if we could have something similar in Metricbeat, and thus, we created the concept of Metricbeat light modules.
</p><p>Light modules are a new way of defining Metricbeat 
modules based on existing implementations. They don't contain any Go 
code — all functionality is provided by existing metricsets. They can be
 seen as predefined configurations for generic metricsets. They speed up
 the development of new modules for services whose monitoring is based 
on protocols we already support, and they provide a way to share 
existing Metricbeat configurations and dashboards.
</p><h2>Implementing Metricbeat light modules</h2><p>Metricbeat light modules keep the known structure of modules and metricsets, but 
instead of using Go code to define the modules and metricsets, files containing definitions as metadata are used.
</p><p>Each light module includes a <code>module.yml</code> file with the list of light metricsets, and for each metricset, there is a directory with a <code>manifest.yml</code> with its definition. Light modules included in the <a href="https://www.github.com/elastic/beats">beats</a> repository can also provide documentation files, dashboards, field mappings, or automated tests, just like any other module.
</p><p>A basic light module with two metricsets would have a structure like this one:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">├── module.yml
├── _meta
│   ├── config.yml
│   └── docs.asciidoc
├── metricset1
│   ├── manifest.yml
│   └── _meta
│       └── docs.asciidoc
└── metricset2
    ├── manifest.yml
    └── _meta
        └── docs.asciidoc
</pre><p>A manifest file includes a reference to an existing 
metricset, allowing to override or define new defaults. For example the 
following file would define a module based on the metricset 
	<em><code>somemetricset</code></em> of the module <em><code>somemodule</code></em>, and would set a couple of default settings:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">input:
  module: somemodule
  metricset: somemetricset
  defaults:
    some_option: foo
    other_option: bar
  default: true
</pre><p>A Metricbeat user could then use it with a configuration similar to the one of any other module:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">- module: module
  metricsets: ['metricset1', 'metricset2']
  ...
</pre><p>Light modules are designed as a fallback mechanism to current modules — if a module is included in Metricbeat configuration and is not found along the registered ones, then Metricbeat looks for an existing light module and metricset with the given name in its home path. If it is found, it is loaded and instantiated.
</p><p>As we have seen, a light module manifest references a metricset as its input implementation. The reference metricset must be an existing native metricset — it cannot reference another light module. The final module would be instantiated and customized with the default settings defined in the manifest.
</p><p>There can be modules that mix native metricsets with light metricsets, for example we plan to implement some AWS metricsets, like <code>elb</code>, as light modules based on the AWS <code>cloudwatch</code> metricset.
</p><p>The first module implemented as a light module is for CockroachDB; its beta version is included in Metricbeat 7.3.
</p><h2>Example: CockroachDB light module</h2><p><a href="https://github.com/cockroachdb/cockroach">CockroachDB</a> is a good service to use as an initial example because it can be monitored using an existing metricset — the <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-prometheus-collector.html">Prometheus collector</a> — but it requires a small customization to set the proper metrics endpoint (it uses <code>/_status/vars</code> as the metrics path instead of the default <code>/metrics</code>). If we wanted to monitor CockroachDB with the Prometheus collector metricset, we could do it using a configuration like the following one:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">- module: prometheus
  metricsets: ['collector']
  hosts: ['localhost:8080']
  metrics_path: '/_status/vars'
</pre><p>If we want to migrate this configuration to a light module, we can do it with the following files:
</p><p><code>x-pack/metricbeat/module/cockroachdb/module.yml</code>
</p><pre class="prettyprint">name: cockroachdb
metricsets:
- status
</pre><p><code>x-pack/metricbeat/module/cockroachdb/status/manifest.yml</code>
</p><pre class="prettyprint">input:
  module: prometheus
  metricset: collector
  defaults:
    metrics_path: /_status/vars
default: true
</pre><p>With this module definition we are telling Metricbeat to use the <code>collector</code> metricset of the <code>prometheus</code> module, but replacing the default <code>metrics_path</code> with <code>/_status/vars</code>. We are also indicating that this is a default metricset of this module, so it is instantiated if no other metricset is specified in the configuration file.
</p><p>Despite not having code, testing of this module is done in a similar way to other modules. But because its definition won't be included in the test binary files, we have to take a few things into account.
</p><p>First, base module and metricset may not be registered in the modules registry of the testing binary, so we have to explicitly import it so it gets registered:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">import (
  _ "github.com/elastic/beats/metricbeat/module/prometheus"
  _ "github.com/elastic/beats/metricbeat/module/prometheus/collector"
)
</pre><p>And the modules registry doesn’t know anything about light modules in 
test binaries, so we have to explicitly indicate where they are located. 
They will be loaded from this location as configuration files, so we 
also remove the permission checks that are applied to these files. Both 
things can be done in an 
	<code>init()</code> function in the test files of the module:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">func init() {
  os.Setenv("BEAT_STRICT_PERMS", "false")
  mb.Registry.SetSecondarySource(
    xpackmb.NewLightModulesSource("../../../module"))
}
</pre><p>Once the module is ready, it can be used in a way that feels familiar to Metricbeat users:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">- module: cockroachdb
  metricsets: ['status']
  hosts: ['localhost:8080']
</pre><p>Events generated look like these:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">{
 "@timestamp": "2019-05-22T10:00:30.818Z",
 "event": {
  "dataset": "cockroachdb.status",
  "duration": 29065910,
  "module": "cockroachdb"
 },
 "metricset": {
  "name": "status"
 },
 "prometheus": {
  "labels": {
   "le": "1638399",
   "store": "1"
  },
  "metrics": {
   "raft_process_applycommitted_latency_bucket": 106946,
   "raft_process_commandcommit_latency_bucket": 111112,
   "raft_process_handleready_latency_bucket": 21243,
   "raft_process_logcommit_latency_bucket": 53080
  }
 },
 "service": {
  "address": "172.17.0.2:8080",
  "type": "cockroachdb"
 }
}
</pre><p>They are events like the ones that would be generated by the Prometheus 
collector metricset if used on its own, but with the event and service 
information replaced to indicate the module and dataset used.
</p><p>Prometheus namespacing is intentionally kept so it reuses the fields mappings of the original metricset.
</p><p>Finally, this module also includes a dashboard that makes use of some of the available metrics, like:
</p><ul>
	<li><code>prometheus.metrics.sql_conns</code> for the number of active SQL connections</li>
	<li><code>prometheus.metrics.replicas</code> for the number of replicas</li>
	<li><code>prometheus.metrics.ranges_unavailable</code> for the number of unavailable ranges</li>
</ul><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt65c9430e7da6e918/5d487981c1c3087f2e8337d4/light-modules-dashboard-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt65c9430e7da6e918" alt="Dashboard showing active SQL connections, replicas, and unavailable ranges " style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><h2>What's next?</h2><p>There are many use cases where this new framework for developing Metricbeat 
modules can be useful. Besides the example based on Prometheus seen in this article, we are already working on the 
	<a href="https://github.com/elastic/beats/pull/12952">AWS ELB metricset</a> based on the <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-aws-cloudwatch.html">cloudwatch metricset</a>, and we also plan to start working on supporting more Java services using the <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-jolokia.html">Jolokia module</a>.
</p><p>On the tooling side, we think that <code>metricbeat</code> subcommands give users a complete toolset for contributing new modules without more requirements than the Elastic Stack itself. In this sense we are thinking about ways to extend 
	<code>metricbeat test</code>, or introduce new subcommands that can be used for light modules validation.
</p><p>Finally, we invite you to create your own light modules. If you're already using one of the mentioned generic modules to monitor some services, consider migrating this configuration to a module others can use.
</p><p>If you want to learn more, take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/beats/issues/12270">design issue</a>, the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/beats/pull/12465">initial implementation</a>, and the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/beats/pull/12467">pull request for the CockroachDB module</a>. And if you have any questions, remember that we are always happy to help on the <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/c/beats">Discuss forums</a>.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/introducing-metricbeat-light-modules</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/introducing-metricbeat-light-modules</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jaime Soriano]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Keeping up with Kibana: August 2nd, 2019 edition]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Kibana UI Weekly&nbsp;Update! <br>
</p>
<h4>We are hiring!</h4>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://grnh.se/01f01f5c1">Kibana Applications Security Engineer</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://grnh.se/24ddf24d1">Kibana - Senior JavaScript Engineer</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://grnh.se/a12f57d31">Kibana - Platform JavaScript Engineer (Node.js)</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://jobs.elastic.co/jobs/kibana/distributed-amer-or-western-europe/director-sr-director-product-management-kibana/1571633#/">Director / Sr Director Product Management - Kibana</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://grnh.se/7f51db4a1">Kibana - Visualisations Engineer</a></li>
</ul>
</br>
<h3>Security</h3>
<h4>Copy to Space<br></h4>
<p>The PR to make the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41688">spaces saved object type hidden</a>, which allows the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/38014">copy to space API</a> to explicitly specify the namespace merged this week. We’re continuing to work with design on <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/39002">the UI for copy to space</a> and we’re getting close!
</p>
<h4>Allow individual privileges to be excluded from base privileges
</h4>
<p>The Code application consumes Kibana resources in a rather unprecedented manner. As such, we’re considering limiting the users which are able to clone Code repos. To enable this pattern, we began working on adding <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42470">the ability for individual privileges to be excluded from the base privileges</a>. This will enable us to grant read-only access to Code with the “all” base privilege.
</p>
<h3>Platform&nbsp;</h3>
<p>The HttpService saw a lot of progress this week. The <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41894">new route handler interface</a> has been merged, and PRs are in review for <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42331">comprehensive documentation</a> and some <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42442">API polish for consistency</a>. We’re getting very close to being able to open up these APIs to plugin developers.
</p>
<p>The <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/39891">SavedObjectsClient for the browser</a> in review and should be merged next week.&nbsp;
</p>
<p>This week we also merged <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41251">the ContextService</a> to support more ergonomic access to Core services inside asynchronous handlers. This is a fundamental building block in the New Platform design and unblocks the AppService and HttpService. The AppService is nearing completion and final testing before PR review.
</p>
<h3>Operations</h3>
<p>Last week we advanced the static fs in several fields. We are now returning the files and the base folders added as well as the possibility to declare exclusions on generation. Additionally we have also fixed a bug that prevented us from read from a relative path inside the static filesystem.&nbsp;
</p>
<h3>App Architecture</h3>
<h4>Data Access Services
</h4>
<p>We merged a final implementation of the POC to <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/40238">make expressions cancelable</a> by adding a new handler in the interpreter. This will be an important feature as we work toward implementing query cancellation more broadly.
</p>
<h4>New Platform Migration
</h4>
<p>We've <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42164">TypeScriptified and moved Inspector to the New Platform “inspector” plugin</a>, which is now our second stateful New Platform plugin 🎉 We also&nbsp;handled some much-needed <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42238">cleanup to the data plugin</a>, which brings it in line with the conventions we recommend in <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/blob/master/src/core/MIGRATION.md">the migration guide</a>, and also took some time for <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41638">more Angular cleanup</a>.
</p>
<p>We're still pushing forward on shimming vis types. RIght now <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42348">tag cloud</a>, <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42240">metric vis</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/39169">TSVB</a> are all in the final stages of review & expected to merge very soon.
</p>
<p>Lastly, we added some <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42261">Karma mocks for new platform services</a>, beginning with the data plugin. A <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42302">PR has been opened against the migration guide</a> with more background on these mocks, and how they differ from the existing new platform jest mocks.
</p>
<h3>Kibana App (Visualizations, Sharing, Discover, Reporting)</h3>
<h4>Lens (New visual editor)</h4>
<p>The biggest work this week was on:
</p>
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41784">Performance improvements (merged)</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42093">Chart switching (merged)</a></li>
	<li>Filter bar and time picker (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42031">in progress</a>)</li>
	<li>Better suggestion logic (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42052">merged</a>, <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42344">open</a>, <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42537">open</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>Our chart switcher is now much more graphical, and is able to indicate when users are losing data:
</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt8057cbb9b1a61ac8/5d49c4f2302f4743540141ef/lens_chart_switching.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt8057cbb9b1a61ac8" alt="lens_chart_switching.png">&nbsp;<br>
</p>
<h4>Discover
</h4>
<p>Fine tuned&nbsp;feedback to PR<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41918"> #41918</a>. Et voilá, we’ve merged a long requested feature, sorting on multiple columns (151<a href="https://emojipedia.org/thumbs-up-sign/">👍</a>). Furthermore we found a way to deangularize DocViewer without locking out 3rd party plugins still using Angular for now, ongoing PR <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42116">#42116</a>.&nbsp;
</p>
<h3>Design</h3>
<h4>Eui Data Grid
</h4>
<p>This week saw major progress on EUI data grid, our upcoming component for managing large sets of tabular results. We landed three big PRs into our feature branch: one that <a href="https://github.com/elastic/eui/pull/2187">added basic aria-controls</a> and accessibility, one that <a href="https://github.com/elastic/eui/pull/2165">added pagination</a> and one that set up some <a href="https://github.com/elastic/eui/pull/2176">initial customizable styling</a>. This week we hope to get some toolbar like management for common actions. Target is still to get this in people’s hands by the end of the month.
</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt7bf0459bef1fefb7/5d49c4d2302f4743540141e9/table_component.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt7bf0459bef1fefb7" alt="table_component.gif">
</p>
<h4>Elastic Charts in EUI docs
</h4>
<p>This one's been a back-burner project for us, but we’re making good progress on getting snippets and documentation into EUI for how to best utilize Elastic Charts. This should give folks some best practices for styling beautiful visualizations.
</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt606ec20f81c03505/5d49c4c25c5bf77f34eb813d/chart_design.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt606ec20f81c03505" alt="chart_design.gif">
</p>
<h3>Stack Services
</h3>
<h4>Alerting<br></h4>
<p>A bunch of cleanup, bug fixing and cleanup of the alerting code. See <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41933">#41933</a>; <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42273">#42273</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42393">#42393</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42493">#42493</a>;&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41917">#41917</a>
</p>
<p>Security plugin now has the ability to create API keys <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/41389">#41389</a>. This will be used for executing requests on behalf of a user in alerting when we don’t have the user’s request to authenticate to Elasticsearch.
</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>That's all for this week. <br>
	Until next time, <br>
	Kibana Team
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/keeping-up-with-kibana-2019-08-02</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/keeping-up-with-kibana-2019-08-02</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Raya Fratkina]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 17:23:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ruby on Rails application monitoring with the Elastic Stack]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h2 id="rubyonrailsapplicationmonitoringwiththeelasticstack">Ruby on Rails application monitoring with the Elastic Stack</h2>
<p>Recently, at the Tochigi Ruby Conference, I gave a presentation on monitoring Ruby on Rails applications.</p>
<p>Here’s a quick overview. <a href="https://noti.st/johtani/eJPLbZ/elastic">The slides (in Japanese) are here</a>. The application used in the demo is <a href="https://github.com/johtani/monitoring-ruby-app">published on GitHub</a>.</p>
<h2 id="pointstokeepinmindforapplicationmonitoring">Points to keep in mind for application monitoring</h2>
<p>I introduced the following monitoring areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>Uptime monitoring</li>
<li>Host and application metrics</li>
<li>Monitoring logs</li>
<li>Application performance monitoring (APM)</li>
</ul>
<p>The app created for this demo posts questions from participants.
During a session, participants post any questions they have, and at the end of the session there is a Q&amp;A session based on the posted questions.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt38ecad7ea188982d/5d42197f48143c39c4b3e211/monitoring-ruby-app-demo-blog.png" alt="Overview of app" /></p>
<p>Some details about the application:</p>
<p>It is composed of a frontend (NGINX + Rails) and backend (PostgreSQL).
On each server, <a href="/products/beats/metricbeat">Metricbeat</a>, <a href="/products/beats/filebeat">Filebeat</a>, <a href="/products/beats/auditbeat">Auditbeat</a>, and <a href="/products/beats/packetbeat">Packetbeat</a> were installed, along with <a href="/products/beats/heartbeat">Heartbeat</a> on the backend and the <a href="/guide/en/apm/agent/ruby/2.x/index.html">Elastic APM Ruby Agent</a> on the frontend. Then, logs and metrics for each type of monitoring explained below were collected.
Also, setup was minimized by using <a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> for data storage and visualization. Elasticsearch Service allows you to set up Elastic APM Server, Elasticsearch, and Kibana in a cloud environment. There’s also a 14-day trial, so if you’re interested in monitoring you can get started right away.</p>
<h2 id="monitoringthevariousareas">Monitoring the various areas</h2>
<h3 id="uptimemonitoring">Uptime monitoring</h3>
<p>The most important thing in monitoring is whether or not the application status as seen from outside the application is normal.
The Elastic Stack enables easy monitoring of HTTP, TCP, and ICMP using <a href="/products/beats/heartbeat">Heartbeat</a>.
For this demo, I used the following <a href="https://github.com/johtani/monitoring-ruby-app/blob/master/gcp/templates/heartbeat.yml">monitoring settings</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>ICMP: each server</li>
<li>HTTP: Rails application page, NGINX server status page</li>
<li>TCP: PostgreSQL port 5432</li>
</ul>
<pre><code>heartbeat.monitors:
  - type: icmp
    schedule: '@every 5s'
    hosts:
      - frontend.{{ domain }}
      - backend.{{ domain }}

  - type: http
    urls: ["https://www.{{ domain }}/about/about"]
    schedule: "@every 10s"
    timeout: 3s
    check.response.status: 200

  - type: http
    urls: ["https://www.{{ domain }}/server-status"]
    schedule: "@every 10s"
    timeout: 3s
    check.response.status: 200

  - type: tcp
    hosts: ["tcp://backend.{{ domain }}:5432"]
    schedule: "@every 10s"
    timeout: 3s
    name: postgresql
</code></pre>
<p>You can view this data in the <a href="/guide/en/kibana/7.2/uptime-overview.html">Uptime app</a> in Kibana. The Uptime app allows you to easily monitor the availability of servers or apps.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt6772b02c5c4a27bf/5d4219aeeb241003ac331f6f/monitoring-ruby-uptime-blog.jpg" alt="Uptime dashboard in Kibana" /></p>
<p>With the release of 7.2 came the ability to move from the Uptime app to our other observability apps (Logs, Infrastructure, and APM) with one click.</p>
<h3 id="hostandapplicationmetrics">Host and application metrics</h3>
<p>Once you have found the issue with your server or application, the next step is often to check metrics — the state of resources such as CPU and memory.</p>
<p><a href="/products/beats/metricbeat">Metricbeat</a> is a part of the Elastic Stack that is used to collect host information (CPU usage, memory, files, disk I/O, etc.) for monitoring. In addition, it can also collect statistical information (metrics) about NGINX and PostgreSQL.
Check out the <a href="/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-modules.html">Metricbeat modules documentation</a> for more information.</p>
<p>Host information can be viewed on the following screen using the Infrastructure app in Kibana.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltdd81b49a6e39f9c5/5d4219ed17e47e044554625c/monitoring-ruby-host-info-blog.jpg" alt="Host information shown in Kibana" /></p>
<h3 id="monitoringlogs">Monitoring logs</h3>
<p>Logs are useful when you want to get detailed information about a problem.
This demo operated under the assumption that PostgreSQL database server processes had stopped.
Also, the PostgreSQL port number was specified as a target for uptime monitoring by <a href="/products/beats/heartbeat">Heartbeat</a>, but the demo proceeded without displaying it.</p>
<p>In such cases, the problem often becomes clear when you look at the application server logs (the connection error was output to the logs even in this demo).
However, for application server logs, depending on the type of server or application, it may not be a good idea to ingest the text logs directly into the Elastic Stack.
This demo used a library called <a href="https://github.com/roidrage/lograge">Lograge</a>, and logs were output as one JSON per request to Rails and then ingested.
It is also possible to use the <a href="/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.2/multiline-examples.html"><code>multiline</code></a> function to ingest logs. However, if you are considering ingesting logs from the application development stage, output in JSON format, as in this case, will make ingest easier.</p>
<p>In the demo, the filter “application: ruby” was added on the Discover screen, returning the actual application logs and demonstrating the flow for identifying problems. This application field is a tag added in the <a href="https://github.com/johtani/monitoring-ruby-app/blob/master/gcp/templates/filebeat.yml#L9">Filebeat settings</a>. By adding information such as where the target log file was obtained, it is possible to further narrow down the information more easily.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt1aff4f558508f5e3/5d421a1beb241003ac331f7b/monitoring-ruby-discover-blog.jpg" alt="Filtering by Ruby applications" /></p>
<p>Other logs may also be important.
<a href="/products/beats/auditbeat">Auditbeat</a> collects audit logs such as those for process stops/starts, file tampering detection, and logins.
If the process has stopped, who stopped it, and when? It is possible to find out by looking at audit logs. The screen below shows an Auditbeat dashboard of logs related to the starting and stopping of PostgreSQL processes.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt1ee6e2a84f280a21/5d421a4ca15cf339be7e56f1/monitoring-ruby-auditbeat-dashboard-blog.jpg" alt="Auditbeat dashboard of logs" /></p>
<h3 id="apm">APM</h3>
<p>Finally, there’s APM. Information on the inside of the application is also important for quickly finding problems inside the application. The uptime monitoring, metrics, and logs that we have discussed so far all observe the application or system from the outside. However, in order to analyze information such as which application processes are slow, it is necessary to add debug and measurement logs and deploy your application.</p>
<p>That’s where <a href="/solutions/apm">Elastic APM</a> comes in.
You just load an APM agent into the application you are developing and the agent measures the application and sends the measurement data to Elasticsearch.</p>
<p>When using Elastic APM with Ruby on Rails, configure the agent as follows.
First, add the gem for the agent that you’d like to use to the Gemfile.</p>
<pre><code># For Elastic APM
gem 'elastic-apm'
</code></pre>
<p>Then, create a file called <code>elastic_apm.yml</code> in the <code>config</code> directory, and add your server URL and secret token.</p>
<pre><code>server_url: &lt;%= ENV['ELASTIC_APM_SERVER_URL'] %&gt;
secret_token: &lt;%= ENV['ELASTIC_APM_SECRET_TOKEN'] %&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>That’s it! The agent will automatically measure the processing time of actions and SQL calls within the Rails framework.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt36c7ac7670ab3051/5d421a81e6adda03a744f89c/monitoring-ruby-transactions-blog.jpg" alt="Dashboard showing transactions in Kibana" /></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt72934e923348d4ea/5d421a9f48143c39c4b3e21d/monitoring-ruby-transaction-sample-blog.jpg" alt="Showing a transaction sample" /></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blte6dba5812c9bccb0/5d421ab9e6adda03a744f8a2/monitoring-ruby-span-details-blog.jpg" alt="Drilling down to show span details" /></p>
<p>You also get data about errors, so you can use these instead of logs to find problems.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt4e34fd17cc1feb20/5d421ae45cd7063da002111c/monitoring-ruby-errors-blog.jpg" alt="Viewing errors in Kibana" /></p>
<p>Some developers may want to include not only framework methods but also their own instrumentation. In that case, you can <a href="/guide/en/apm/agent/ruby/2.x/custom-instrumentation.html#custom-instrumentation">create your own custom instrumentation</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltb370bc60049485da/5d421b023d6fea3947615f6b/monitoring-ruby-instrumentation-blog.png" alt="Showing custom instrumentation in Kibana" /></p>
<p>In this way, by observing systems and applications from multiple vantage points, it is possible to solve problems quickly. The new term Observability is being used more frequently to refer to this phenomenon — <a href="/blog/observability-with-the-elastic-stack">check out our related blog post on observability with the Elastic Stack</a>.
By collecting measurement data in one place with the Elastic Stack, you can easily correlate metrics, logs, and APM data from the same time period.
I hope you’ll take advantage of it!</p>
<p>If you’d like to see a demo in person, there are plenty of opportunities at conferences or meetups, so <a href="/contact">please feel free to let us know</a>!</p>
<p>Or, you can instrument your own applications and visualize your logs, metrics, and uptime data with a free trial of the <a href="/cloud">Elasticsearch Service</a>, or download the <a href="/downloads/">default distribution</a> and run locally.</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/ruby-on-rails-application-monitoring-with-the-elastic-stack</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/ruby-on-rails-application-monitoring-with-the-elastic-stack</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jun Ohtani]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Week in Elasticsearch and Apache Lucene - 2019-08-02]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h3 id="elasticsearch">Elasticsearch</h3>
<h4 id="automaticsearchcancellation">Automatic Search Cancellation</h4>
<p>We continued to work on&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/43377">cancelling searches</a>&nbsp;when the connection that made the request gets closed. We are now working on hardening the tests but the main functionality is ready.  The Kibana team has been working on making <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/40238">Kibana</a> <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/pull/42035">close</a> the connection when the user navigates away from the page.</p>
<h4 id="painlessdateexamples">Painless Date Examples</h4>
<p>We&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44985">added some date usage examples</a>&nbsp;for painless. We also&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44874">fixed a casting issue</a>&nbsp;related to the temporary compatilbity class JodaCompatibleZonedDateTime which we added for the transition from joda to java time. With the new auto casting behavior between JCZDT and ZDT, our example documentation can now refer to ZonedDateTime even though the concrete class is JCZDT.</p>
<h4 id="geo">Geo</h4>
<p>With the upcoming release of cartesian shapes the pieces are in place to begin adding support for geospatial projections. This will enable the Elasticsearch Geo community to index geospatial geometries in their native projection without loss of precision resulting from the requirement to reproject back to WGS84 lat/lon to index in Lucene. Oil &amp; Gas users, for example, have a lot of data in NAD27 and NAD83 based projections, the academic community has a lot of data in State Plane projections, and NASA and other government agencies use a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.giss.nasa.gov/tools/gprojector/help/projections/">large variety of spatial projections</a>&nbsp;(bacon globular being one of my particular favorites). Work has begun to explore the performance tradeoffs of using either&nbsp;<a href="http://sis.apache.org/">Apache SIS</a>&nbsp;or&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/locationtech/proj4j">Proj4J</a>&nbsp;(both Apache 2 licensed)&nbsp;to handle the reprojection logic vs. rolling our own projection library (something we could do but probably don't need or want to).</p>
<p>We&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44980">merged in the new ShapeFieldMapper</a>, which means indexing arbitrary 2 dimension geometry&nbsp;has landed! Elasticsearch uses can now index any arbitrary 2 dimension (non Geospatial) geometries making it possible to map out virtual worlds, sporting venues, theme parks, and CAD diagrams. Thanks to the awesome team effort to refactor the existing ShapeBuilders, FieldMappers, and QueryBuilders to make this relatively straightforward to integrate and easier to manage. The last piece of the puzzle is to merge the ShapeQueryBuilder PR which adds the ability to query indexed shapes using the familiar GeoJson and WKT formats used in geo_shape queries.</p>
<h4 id="masterresiliencyslowclusterstateupdates">Master Resiliency / Slow Cluster State Updates</h4>
<p>Based on a number of recent support cases that involved slow cluster state updates, we&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45007">significantly improved our logging in this area</a>, adding a lot more detail in various places to allow identifying slow nodes during cluster state publication as well as slow components within these nodes during cluster state application, and this even without requiring to crank up logging levels.</p>
<h4 id="peerrecoveryretentionleases">Peer recovery retention leases</h4>
<p>We&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44853">reinstated the recovery of history from Lucene during peer recovery</a>&nbsp;now that we have all the supporting infrastructure to retain that history using retention leases. Peer recovery will decide whether to perform a file-based recovery or not according to the existence of an appropriate lease (on indices with soft-deletes enabled, which is the default since 7.0). As leases expire after 12 hours, and persist across restarts, we expect clusters to be able to perform operation-based recoveries for replicas that were active at some point in the last 12 hours.</p>
<p>There are still some outstanding tasks in this project. Most notably we now only use the translog for recovering locally (on indices with soft-deletes enabled) and can therefore discard old translog generations much more enthusiastically than we currently do.</p>
<h4 id="clusterprivilegerefactoring">Cluster Privilege Refactoring</h4>
<p>For a long time we've had a plan to make it possible to be more fine-grained with cluster level privileges. For example, the&nbsp;<code>manage</code>&nbsp;privilege allows users to update cluster settings, but that means they are allowed to update&nbsp;<em>all</em>&nbsp;settings - there is no way to restrict a user to specific settings.</p>
<p>Last year, when introducing&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/32309">application privileges</a>&nbsp;we wanted the&nbsp;<code>kibana</code>&nbsp;reserved user to be able to&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/32221">manage its own privileges</a>, but not the privileges of other applications, so we started down the path of having cluster privileges that were&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/32073">could take the request object into account</a>&nbsp;rather than simply authorising on an action name.</p>
<p>With API Keys we wanted to do something similar where any user could be assigned a privilege that allowed them to&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/issues/40031">manage their own API keys</a>, but no one else's. It turns out that the model we had put in place last year didn't quite fit in with what we wanted to do here, so we have been working to&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44932">refactor the cluster privilege model</a>&nbsp;to support this use case.</p>
<p>We're hopeful that this will make it easier to implement some of the finer grained cluster privileges that customers have been asking for.</p>
<h4 id="proxypkiinkibana">Proxy PKI in Kibana</h4>
<p>We merged most of the necessary PRs to the&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/tree/proxied-pki">proxied-pki feature branch</a>, which allows the Kibana team to start working on their changes to support PKI authentication in Kibana.</p>
<h4 id="indexlifecyclemanagement">Index Lifecycle Management</h4>
<p>We added a couple of helpful flags for the ILM explain response output - 'only<em>managed' and 'only</em>errors', these limit the responses either only to indices that currently have a policy, or to indices that have a policy where the policy is currently in the ERROR step. This should help cut down the size of the response that a user has to read when trying to figure out which of their indices is having ILM troubles (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44777">https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44777</a>).</p>
<p>The team had an interesting discussion during our weekly stand-up about supporting indices that use ILM policies with rollover as well as manually rolling over. If a user currently does this, ILM will enter the ERROR state when it goes to automatically roll over the index. We've seen a couple of internal folks hit this as well as customers, so we brainstormed a solution that would allow use to skip the ILM rollover when we detect it has already been done manually outside of ILM (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/issues/44175">https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/issues/44175</a>). This work aims to lower the chance a user can enter the ERROR state, which we would always prefer to avoid.</p>
<h4 id="snapshotlifecyclemanagement">Snapshot Lifecycle Management</h4>
<p>On the SLM side, work continues towards implementing retention for snapshots, the initial snapshot retention predicates have been implemented (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44926">https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44926</a>) which means that we now support expiration based on the time value of a snapshot, a minimum number of snapshots, or a maximum number of snapshots (or any combination of all three). Additionally, performing the actual "delete" of snapshots may take a long amount of time, so we opened a PR to time-bound the amount of time that SLM will spend doing snapshot deletion during retention (<a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45065">https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45065</a>). This is a user configurable setting and will initially be capped at an hour.</p>
<h3 id="lucene">Lucene</h3>
<h4 id="matchesapi">Matches API</h4>
<p>The matches API allows to retrieve positions where a query matches on a per-document basis.&nbsp;</p>
<p>It is implemented in two phases, a match phase where the full query is evaluated to check if the query matches the document and a second phase that creates an iterator over all the positions that match inside the document for the requested fields. When checking if a multi-term query, such as an AutomatonQuery or TermInSetQuery, matches we currently find all matching term iterators up-front, to return a disjunction over all of them. This can be inefficient if we're only interested in finding out if anything matched, and are iterating over a different field to retrieve positions.\
We&nbsp;<a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-8937">improved</a>&nbsp;this&nbsp;by returning immediately when the first matching term is found, and only collecting other matching terms lazily (when we start iterating the positions for that field).</p>
<h4 id="booleanquery">Boolean Query</h4>
<p>We already support early termination of constant score queries (queries that give the same score to all documents) when the hit count is not requested but some cases were missing. For instance a boolean query that is only composed of filters will assign a score of 0 to all documents but the support for early termination is this case was not implemented. We worked on a&nbsp;<a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-8935">patch</a>&nbsp;to handle this case efficiently without the need to wrap the boolean query in another high level query.</p>
<h4 id="other">Other</h4>
<ul>
<li>The&nbsp;<a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-8937">minimal french stemmer</a>&nbsp;now avoids stemming numbers.</li>
<li>The&nbsp;<a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-8934">tests</a>&nbsp;of the Korean Dictionary builder have been merged to the main src directory and are now part of the general test suite (ant test).</li>
<li><a href="https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LUCENE-8921">IndexSearcher.termStatistics</a>&nbsp;should not require TermStates but only docFreq and totalTermFreq.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="changes">Changes</h3>
<h4 id="changesinelasticsearch">Changes in Elasticsearch</h4>
<p>Changes in 8.0:</p>
<ul>
<li>Add missing dependency on plugin bundle task <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45103">#45103</a></li>
<li>Rename HLRC 'indexlifecycle' components to 'ilm' <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44982">#44982</a></li>
<li>BREAKING: Remove client feature tracking <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44929">#44929</a></li>
<li>RestController should not consume request content <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44902">#44902</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Changes in 7.4:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove unnecessary plugin application and project configuration <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45100">#45100</a></li>
<li>Updated slm API spec parameters and URL <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44797">#44797</a></li>
<li>Use IndicesModule named writables in elasticsearch-shard tool <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45036">#45036</a></li>
<li>More logging for slow cluster state application <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45007">#45007</a></li>
<li>Remove task null check in TransportAction <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45014">#45014</a></li>
<li>Stop Recreating Wrapped Handlers in RestController <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44964">#44964</a></li>
<li>Improve errors when TLS files cannot be read <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44787">#44787</a></li>
<li>[GEO] New ShapeFieldMapper for indexing cartesian geometries <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44980">#44980</a></li>
<li>Adds usage stats for vectors: <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44512">#44512</a></li>
<li>[ML][Data Frames] unify validation exceptions between PUT/_preview <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44983">#44983</a></li>
<li>[ML][Data Frame] add support for bucket_selector <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44718">#44718</a></li>
<li>Remove leniency during replay translog in peer recovery <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44989">#44989</a></li>
<li>Explicitly fail if a realm only exists in keystore <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44471">#44471</a></li>
<li>Fix JodaCompatibleZonedDateTime casts in Painless <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44874">#44874</a></li>
<li>Remove leniency in reset engine from translog <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44711">#44711</a></li>
<li>Geo: fix geo query decomposition <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44924">#44924</a></li>
<li>TaskListener#onFailure to accept Exception instead of Throwable <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44946">#44946</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Changes in 7.3:</p>
<ul>
<li>Do not use scroll when finding duplicate API key <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45026">#45026</a></li>
<li>Sparse role queries can throw an NPE <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45053">#45053</a></li>
<li>bug fix about elasticsearch.common.settings.Settings.processSetting <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44047">#44047</a></li>
<li>Fix version logic after 7.3 release (BWC) <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/45077">#45077</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Changes in 6.8:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fix early termination of aggregators that run with breadth-first mode <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/pull/44963">#44963</a></li>
</ul>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/this-week-in-elasticsearch-and-apache-lucene-2019-08-02</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/this-week-in-elasticsearch-and-apache-lucene-2019-08-02</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Jim Ferenczi,Zachary Tong,Ryan Ernst,Tim Vernum,Yannick Welsch,Tom Callahan,Lee Hinman]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 04:04:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Cytech harnessed the Elastic Stack to build a BI tool in 6 months]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><em>This is one in an occasional series of community driven stories born out of our <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/elasticstories">#ElasticStories</a> campaign.</em>
</p><hr><p>Cytech Mobile is a technology provider in the telecoms sector. We build our own software products around mobile messaging, marketing and payments and we offer them to our customers all around the world. Our flagship product called <a href="https://www.cytechmobile.com/mCore">mCore</a> is a cloud based software  to manage <a href="https://www.techopedia.com/definition/33754/a2p-messaging">Application-to-Person</a> (A2P) SMS trafficking  for companies in the wholesale as well as retail SMS messaging business.   A2P means communications sent from a software or machine to a subscriber  as opposed to Person-to-Person SMS, for instance marketing messages or One-Time-Passwords.  We serve two types of businesses in that market.on the one hand retail, which means relatively small volumes of SMS a company would need to send to customers or partners, and on the other hand wholesale companies targeting SMS providers and aggregators who are active in both the retail and wholesale layers — which represents a way higher volume of traffic. We have more than 1 billion transactions per year through our platforms in 10 different countries. The mCore platform is composed of different add-ons including <a href="https://www.cytechmobile.com/mcore/dashboards/">mCore Dashboards</a>, a business intelligence tool, which we’ve based on the Elastic Stack. I will talk about the development of that product in more detail in this blog.
</p><h2>Searching for a business intelligence tool</h2><p>Back in 2010, most of our customers didn't really take advantage of their data so they could better understand their business, find potential issues and focus on what really matters.</p><p>As all our competitors did, we tried different approaches in the past to offer a set of visualisations:</p><ul>
	<li>Offer the reporting and alerting inside the messaging suite which only worked for low volume traffic.</li>
	<li>Use a lightweight library that can render the charts with less resources. Still, it proved not a scalable solution.</li>
	<li>Moving  to the Amazon Cloud, we had the resources and we could elastically alter them for each of our customers. But as the bottleneck still was the database, it didn't really make any significant difference.</li>
</ul><p>Have a read-only replica of the database for reporting only and that didn't interfere with the other operations of the platform.  Prior to mCore Dashboard, this is the solution we had been using so far but it's been expensive to maintain, extend, not designed for free-text search and not suitable for service monitoring.
</p><p>Again these approaches weren’t good enough. That's why we looked for something that could  cover all the aspects of our customers' needs: search, reporting, monitoring and alerting. In 2017 we looked around and  we came across Elastic. We were surprised to discover it was covering most items of our wishlist. It took us less than a week to decide that it’s worth it to give it a try as it fitted very well with our needs. First it was a platform and not a black box. We could build our visualizations on top of it, prepare and adapt our data and shape it the way it would work well with our  mCore platform. The open source nature was also a key differentiator. We have used many open source projects to develop our products, and we love the philosophy behind it. We are convinced that the free access to the code makes software products more resilient and secure. We are also very familiar with the licenses and the way Elastic is developed as our development team contributes to a number of open source projects. Finally, Kibana made the difference. We could easily create charts and graphs and, although at that time it wasn’t so advanced, it was obvious to us that Kibana’s roadmap was aligned with our product’s needs.
</p><h2>Implementing the Elastic Stack</h2><p>Messaging and payments transactions are stored in a relational database and we had to find a way to ingest them into Elasticsearch before we could search, transform and visualise them. It took our team about a week to come up with a way to do it using Logstash. As soon as we had data coming into Elasticsearch, we were sure we could pretty much cover the top 10 requirements of our new product, mCore Dashboards. The most important of them were fast, full-text search, alerting for unexpected incidents, reporting for the top-level management and of being capable of handling a great amount of data. We installed our own Elastic Stack on-premise on Amazon Cloud next to the mCore platform. But there were a couple of very important things missing. Initially, we couldn’t offer our customers user management, alerting and reporting that were then part of the Elastic subscription. The licensing cost wasn’t compatible with our pricing structure.
</p><p>mCore uses a SaaS model and its customers pay a monthly or yearly fee. It wasn’t easy to convince them to pay a substantial amount of extra money for our new BI addon, mCore Dashboards. At that point in time we had a discussion with Elastic, and it was then that Elastic Cloud was launched. It was exactly what we needed. It was 100% compatible with our offering in terms of pricing model and the cost was affordable for our customers. It also included the features that were necessary for our product so we moved to Elasticsearch Service on Cloud. Our mCore platform is sending live denormalized data to  Elasticsearch and our customers can login and have access to the data. They can get a high level picture about their business or dig into their data to try and  answer crucial questions about efficiency and performance.
</p><p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt9628b210c573d7f7/5d3ed72065d74225ef260d76/Cytech-image1.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt9628b210c573d7f7" alt="Cytech performance dashboard" width="710" height="685" style="width: 710px; height: 685px; display: block; margin: auto;"><br>
</p><h2>Use Cases of mCore Dashboards</h2><p>For instance, they can check messaging traffic: if it is normally delivered to their partners, if and when they have peak traffic or even if they lose money. The wholesale SMS and messaging business is really complex as all the stakeholders have connections and agreements with each other and routes quality and prices are constantly changing. One of our partners who was running a Premium SMS mobile payment business had a customer who decided to charge the wrong network subscribers. The result was that our partner wasn’t making any money out of this and their revenue share fell below a certain threshold. Immediately, they received an alert from mCore Dashboards and they could investigate what happened to solve the issue. It saved them time and money and, within 20 minutes, the system was up and running again properly.
</p><p>Another similar example comes from one of our partners, which is getting revenue from the network operator. They keep a small share and give the remaining amount to their customers. They need a monthly report on the amount they need to pay their customers and the amount they need to request from the network operator.  Getting the monthly report used to take a whole day and involve  people from different departments. Now mCore Dashboards produces and sends the report automatically every first of the month to the account managers. We received positive feedback from customers who tried  mCore Dashboards which allowed them to easily get reports emailed to them and therefore save time and money. This convinced us to keep on developing mCore Dashboards. We want  to install it for all our customers and make the necessary customisations and trainings so they can create their own dashboards as well as get personalized alerts and reports.
</p><h2>Next steps with Elastic</h2><p>We are very interested in the machine learning feature of Elastic to discover anomalies in payments and message traffic. We are currently experimenting with it and it has pretty good results. For example, we receive alerts when the traffic grows above the normal threshold or is very low. We also receive alerts when the delivery ratio falls significantly which means that there is a potential issue with a connection or a route.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blte280d44f13ecdcb3/5d3ed71e0c2b8f2183f00c0d/Cytech-image2.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blte280d44f13ecdcb3" alt="Cytech traffic dashboard" width="683" height="408" style="width: 683px; height: 408px; display: block; margin: auto;"><br>
</p><p>Another feature we’re quite excited about  is Canvas. We are now in the process to present live infographics to our customers and get feedback. Our investment in Elastic is paying dividends as Elastic’s roadmap is well aligned with ours. Before it was Kibana and the dashboards, then Elastic Cloud and SaaS offering, and now machine learning and Canvas. Our plan is to incorporate all the features to mCore Dashboards and present a new standalone product that will be able to deal with data coming not only from mCore but from other platforms as well. We will, hopefully, present this new product at the Mobile World Congress 2020 in February. So stay tuned!
</p><hr><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltbd201de57839042b/5d3ed7208ef8251f7c04e6da/Cytech-author-vagelis.jpg" alt="Vagelis Antoniadis" width="255" height="250" "="" style="float: left; width: 255x; height: 250px; margin: 5px;">
</p><p style="margin-left: 40px;"><span style="font-style: normal;"><em>Vagelis Antoniadis is the CEO and co-founder of Cytech Mobile, a technology company in the area of mobile messaging, payments and marketing, with customers all over the world. He's responsible for driving the company’s business development and strategic business relationships worldwide. With more than 15 years experience in strategy development and solution design he strives for business innovation, applying new technologies in the mobile domain, turning them into successful products. He is also Director of Tech Talks Central, a web radio which covers all the hot topics and trends in the connected world and features interactive interviews with thought leaders of the tech industry.</em></span><br>
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/cytech-harnessed-the-elastic-stack-to-build-a-bi-tool-in-6-months</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/cytech-harnessed-the-elastic-stack-to-build-a-bi-tool-in-6-months</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Vagelis Antoniadis]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Where to find Elastic security experts at Black Hat, BSidesLV, and DEF CON 2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>One of the things that makes Elastic great from both a cultural and technological perspective is its <a href="https://www.elastic.co/community/">community</a>. Community is also critical in cybersecurity. The security space isn't about a single tool or individual, but rather how teams collaborate across various datasets and practices to protect valuable infrastructures. As we approach <a href="https://www.blackhat.com/us-19/">Black Hat</a>, <a href="https://www.bsideslv.org/">BSidesLV</a>, and <a href="https://www.defcon.org/html/defcon-27/dc-27-index.html">DEF CON</a> (AKA “Hacker Summer Camp”) next week, I am proud of the role Elastic is playing to help foster this security community — whether through sponsorships, trainings, or the amazing original research and presentations coming out of the Elastic community itself.
</p><p>Whether you’re on a security team at a three-letter agency, a Global 2000 firm, or even a startup, the Elastic (also known as ELK) Stack is likely part of your arsenal — whether on the surface or behind the scenes. Our technology is core to many of the security tools that SOCs rely on most because of its renowned speed, scale, and relevance.
</p><p>Many organizations have used Elastic as their security analytics platform and home-baked SIEM solution for years. For example, SANS, one of the leaders in security training and certification providers, has long used <a href="https://www.sans.org/course/siem-with-tactical-analytics/course/desc/community">Elasticsearch as their training platform for SIEM</a> — not to mention the countless tools and training programs that leverage Elastic for threat hunting, insider threat, and fraud detection.
</p><p>We recently launched our own <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/siem">Elastic SIEM</a> in Elastic Stack 7.2 and made it part of our free Basic license. The security community is already rapidly adopting and providing feedback on Elastic SIEM...but this is just the start!
</p><h2>Where can you find Elastic this summer?</h2><p>
Here's where you can seek us out in Vegas.
</p><h3>Black Hat</h3><p>At Black Hat we will be at booth #1630. Stop by and say hello! Elastic’s own <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mikepaquette1/">Director of Security Products, Mike Paquette</a> will be presenting <em>Using ML-based Hypotheses for Log-based Threat Hunting</em> at Black Hat on Thursday, August 8 from 12:10 p.m. - 1:00 p.m. in Oceanside G.
</p><h3>BSidesLV</h3><p>We also have a booth at BSidesLV. Elastic security gurus <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/kentbrake/">Kent Brake</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/mrebeschini/">Matteo Rebeschini</a> are leading a hands-on session, <em>Finding Evil with Mitre ATT&CK and the Elastic Stack</em> on Wednesday, August 7 from 2:00 p.m. - 5:55 p.m. at the Platinum Hotel Training Ground 5.
</p><h3>DEF CON</h3><p>During DEF CON, several Elasticians will be at the Blue Team Village helping with the OpenSOC capture the flag from Friday 9:00 a.m. - Sunday 2:00 p.m.
</p><h2>Partners make us stronger</h2><p>We are hosting several private workshops at the Aria Hotel along with a few of our partners on Thursday, August 8 from 9:00 a.m. - 4:00 p.m., followed by a happy hour from 4:00 p.m. - 7:00 p.m. Here’s a breakdown of available sessions — register quickly as they’re filling up fast:
</p><ul>
	<li>9:00 a.m. – 10:00 a.m. Resolvn: <em>Building a Training Environment for Threat Hunting with Elastic SIEM</em></li>
	<li>10:00 a.m. – 11:00 a.m. empow: <em>The End of the Ruling Class: SIEM + AI</em></li>
	<li>12:00 p.m. – 2:00 p.m. (Lunch provided): <em>Threat Hunting & Gathering Lunch & Learn (Neil Desai)</em></li>
	<li>2:00 p.m. Perched: <em>Threat Hunting with the Elastic Stack</em></li>
	<li>3:00 p.m. – 4:00 p.m. Dragos: <em>ICS Vulnerability Assessments Powered by Elasticsearch</em></li>
</ul><p><a href="https://events.elastic.co/elasticblackhatworkshops">Register for these workshops and find more details here</a>.
</p><h2>Elastic Community presentations</h2><p>Don’t just take our word for it. Come see for yourself what the Elastic Security Community has been doing with the power of the Elastic Stack.
</p><ul>
	<li><a href="https://www.bsideslv.org/">BSidesLV</a> Tuesday, August 6 | 3:00 p.m. - 3:55 p.m. <em>The Contemplator Approach: Data Enrichment Through Elastic Stack</em> - Rodrigo Brenes and Pedro Rodriguez</li>
	<li><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/dc27-packet-hacking-villages-workshops-ticket-sales-registration-64561412924">DEF CON</a> Friday, August 9 | 4:45 p.m. - 6:45 p.m. <em>Intel-driven hunts for nation state activity using Elastic SIEM</em> - Resolvn (Sean Donnelly and Peter Hay)</li>
	<li><a href="https://defcon.org/">DEF CON</a> Friday, August 9 | 9:00 a.m. <em>Threat Hunting with the Elastic Stack</em> - Savoy Ballroom, Flamingo (Blue Team Village) (4H)- <a href="https://twitter.com/CyberPraesidium">CyberPraesidium</a> of <a href="https://www.politoinc.com/">Polito Inc</a></li>
</ul><p>I hope to see you all in Las Vegas next week! If you want to learn more about leveraging Elastic for your security needs, please don’t hesitate to stop by our booth at Black Hat or BSidesLV — or come talk to us in our sessions.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/where-to-find-elastic-security-experts-2019</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/where-to-find-elastic-security-experts-2019</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Kenneth Westin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elasticsearch Service is now available on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) in Japan]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to share the news that Elasticsearch Service on Elastic Cloud’s fifth GCP region, Asia Pacific (Tokyo), is now open! Tokyo is our first GCP region in Asia Pacific, complementing the four other <a href="/guide/en/cloud/current/ec-reference-regions.html">GCP regions</a> that Elastic offers globally.
</p><p>“The cloud is critically important for large organizations and SMBs in Japan as companies modernize their IT environments from on-premises, traditional data centers to deploy applications and services in public clouds,” said Tom Kawasaki, Elastic Japan Country Manager. “Google Cloud Platform (GCP) has a growing presence in Japan and we’re excited to partner with Google. This new GCP Tokyo region for Elasticsearch Service will give Japan customers a SaaS-first solution for their search, logging, APM, business analytics, infrastructure monitoring, security use cases and more.”
</p><p>Existing users can start using the GCP Tokyo region on Elasticsearch Service immediately. New users can <a href="https://info.elastic.co/gcp-elasticsearch-service.html">sign up</a> for a free 14-day trial to try it out.
</p><h2>All the features you love, now closer to you and your users
</h2><p><a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service">The Elasticsearch Service on Elastic Cloud</a> is the official hosted Elasticsearch and Kibana service, created and supported by Elastic. It is the only managed Elasticsearch offering to include powerful capabilities like Elastic APM, Elastic SIEM, Elastic Maps, Canvas, machine learning, and much more. These features, combined with operational conveniences like same-day availability of new versions and security patches, zero-downtime upgrades, pre-configured hardware templates for popular use cases, and support from Elastic, make our Elasticsearch Service a popular choice for users looking for a managed Elasticsearch offering.
</p><p>“As a GCP partner as well as an Elastic partner, we’re extremely excited to start using the Elasticsearch Service on the GCP Tokyo region. The gaming industry and other industries in Japan will greatly appreciate this announcement,” said Yusuke Hasegawa, president and CEO of grasys Inc.
</p><p>The Asia Pacific (Tokyo) region, like our other regions, offers all of the Elasticsearch Service features. You can learn more about Elasticsearch Service <a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service/subscriptions">subscriptions</a> on our website.
</p><h2>Deepening the Elastic-Google partnership
</h2><p>With the launch of the GCP Tokyo region on Elasticsearch Service, we are also excited to <a href="/blog/elastic-and-google-team-up-to-bring-a-more-native-elasticsearch-service-experience-on-google-cloud">continue deepening our existing partnership with Google Cloud</a>. Our next new GCP region will be launching in Sydney, Australia.
</p><p>“Google Cloud and Elastic are both committed to the open source community and are excited to announce the expanded availability of Elastic Cloud in GCP’s Tokyo region, and unified billing, coming soon. This brings simplicity and speeds up the time to value realization for joint customers,” said Masato Takahashi, Director, Partnerships, Google Cloud Japan.
</p><h2>More native GCP integrations are on the way
</h2><p>We <a href="/blog/elastic-and-google-team-up-to-bring-a-more-native-elasticsearch-service-experience-on-google-cloud">recently announced</a> that GCP users will soon be able to discover, deploy, and manage Elasticsearch Service in a more native way directly in the GCP Console. When this native integration is available, Elasticsearch Service and GCP customers will have the best possible Elasticsearch as a service experience — from the creators — and use it with the same comfort that native GCP services enjoy in the GCP Console.
</p><p>"Our multi-year partnership with Google Cloud keeps getting stronger. New regions like Tokyo and Sydney, seamless access to the Elasticsearch Service through the Google Cloud Platform Console, and billing through Google Cloud, which is targeted for release this August, are all examples of our mutual investments to create a great user experience in the cloud," said Craig Griffin, Vice President of Business Development at Elastic.
</p><h2>Native GCP Console integration
</h2><p>Elasticsearch Service will be a Managed Partner Service (MPS) discoverable in the main GCP Console where native Google services are provisioned. Lifecycle operations such as creating, scaling, configuring, and re-configuring can be accomplished using familiar GCP-style workflows.
</p><h2>Integrated billing
</h2><p>GCP customers will soon be able to provision Elasticsearch Service through GCP Marketplace and have it count 100% towards their existing committed spend.
</p><h2>Get started with Elasticsearch Service in GCP Tokyo
</h2><p>Existing Elasticsearch Service users can simply log in and select the new GCP Tokyo region when creating a deployment. If you are looking to migrate self-managed workloads, check out <a href="/guide/en/cloud/current/ec-migrate-data.html">our documentation</a>, with more details in <a href="/webinars/migrating-your-elasticsearch-data-to-elastic-cloud">this webinar</a>. We strive to make migration as simple as possible and are focused on making it even better for our customers with every release.
</p><p>New to Elasticsearch Service? Get started with a <a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service/signup">14-day trial today</a> — all you need is an email address. If you still have questions, <a href="/contact">we're here to help</a>.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-service-is-now-available-on-google-cloud-platform-gcp-in-japan</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-service-is-now-available-on-google-cloud-platform-gcp-in-japan</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Pieter Humphrey]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 03:15:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic Stack 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are thrilled to announce that version 7.3 of the Elastic Stack has arrived, and it’s another good one.
</p><p>In this blog, we’ll touch on some of the release highlights. Be sure to check out the dedicated blogs for each product to dive into all the details of what’s new. If you just can’t wait, version 7.3 is available right now on <a href="/products/elasticsearch/service">our Elasticsearch Service</a> — the only hosted Elasticsearch offering to include these new features. Or you can <a href="/start">download the Elastic Stack</a>.
</p><p>Now, on to the reason you’re here — here’s what’s new.
</p><h2>Materialized view? Entity-centric index? Introducing data frames
</h2><p>Say hello to <em>data frames</em>, a new feature that lets you pivot your Elasticsearch data on the fly to create live entity-centric indexes. It’s an exciting feature that opens the door to a new world of analysis, including new machine learning analysis — like outlier detection (which was added as an experimental feature in 7.3), clustering, classification, and more.
</p><p>As with most powerful concepts, this feature is best described with an example. Imagine you want to look for suspicious IP addresses in your web server logs. You might want to look at how many requests were made, the response codes, and the total data transferred for each IP address. Data frames allows you to create a new entity-centric index with a document per unique IP address that tracks each metric of interest — in this case, total requests, count per response status, and sum of bytes transferred. The icing on top is that data frames supports continuous processing, which means that this transformed entity-centric index is automatically updated as new documents are added to the input index.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt0d5d98a9b69d3ab4/5d394361e22851575354410f/dataframes.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt0d5d98a9b69d3ab4" alt="dataframes.gif">
</p><p>With data frames, we have built a powerful engine to transform your data for new kinds of analysis. These live <em>pivots</em> are just the first set of transformations enabled by data frames, and we are excited to introduce more transformations in the future that extend the data frames concept to even more use cases.
</p><p><a href="/blog/elasticsearch-7-3-0-released">Read more about data frames</a>.
</p><h2>Elastic SIEM adds anomaly detection — because rules are not enough
</h2><p>We <a href="/blog/introducing-elastic-siem">introduced our SIEM solution</a>&nbsp;in version 7.2, and we’ve been busy since then.
</p><p>Rules alone rarely catch&nbsp;bad actors. So, we enhanced threat detection and threat hunting workflows in <a href="/products/siem">Elastic SIEM</a> for 7.3 by integrating our machine learning capabilities right into the SIEM app. Users can now easily enable and run a set of machine learning anomaly detection jobs designed to detect specific cyber attack behaviors, right from the SIEM app. The detected anomalies are conveniently displayed on the Hosts and Network views in the SIEM app.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt1ad3eafa2a4c6adb/5d3924c61f2f0457e07e36bb/02-elasticsearch-siem-machine-learning-7-3-0-blog.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt1ad3eafa2a4c6adb" alt="02-elasticsearch-siem-machine-learning-7-3-0-blog.png">
</p><p>Users looking to go beyond the prebuilt jobs can easily add custom anomaly detection jobs using the Machine Learning app.
</p><p>With this integration, it’s now easier than ever to leverage machine learning to help detect attack behaviors. See all the details in <a href="/blog/elastic-siem-7-3-0-released">the Elastic SIEM release blog</a><siem release="" blog="">.</siem>
</p><p>“The Elastic Stack helps us with everything from monitoring for cyber threats to examining crime data,” said Steve Caruso, Director of Information Technology for the Will County, IL Sheriff’s Office. "Version 7.3 gives us even more to love. We're excited to get our hands on machine learning from directly within the SIEM app. We are also looking forward to trying out new features in the Maps app. Enhancements like these are valuable to our crime analysis initiatives for all of Law Enforcement within Will County.”</p><h2>Elastic Maps is generally available
</h2><p>Location has always been a critical part of search — whether investigating the source of attacks on your network, diagnosing slow application response times occurring in a specific region, tracking your delivery trucks in real time, or just trying to find the best burrito nearby. This is why we’ve been working since the beginning (<a href="/blog/geo-location-and-search">0.9.1</a>!) to build faster, more powerful, and more efficient geospatial capabilities in the Elastic Stack.
</p><p>We introduced <a href="/products/maps">Elastic Maps</a> as a beta feature in 6.7 to provide a more intuitive and interactive way to explore and understand geospatial data in Kibana, and laying a solid foundation for the future. And in 7.3, we’re happy to announce that Maps is now production ready.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blta55b0643964d4b45/5d3789c25cb66453b1279c1c/02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-7-3-0.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blta55b0643964d4b45" alt="02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-7-3-0.png">
</p><p>Elastic Maps also adds several new features, the most exciting of which is the ability to upload features, shapes, and layers into maps from GeoJSON files. Other improvements like the ability to plot custom icons and visualizing last known location enhance the overall user experience.
</p><p><a href="/blog/elastic-maps-7-3-0-released">Read the Maps blog</a> for all the details. We’re incredibly proud of how far we’ve come with Elastic Maps, and are excited for our users to experience the new features in 7.3 and exciting features planned in future releases.
</p><h2></h2><h2>Yes, there’s more!
</h2><p>So much more. Check out the individual product blogs for the details on everything we added in 7.3:
</p><ul>
	<li>Elasticsearch introduces voting-only master nodes, adds the long-requested  rare-terms aggregation, a new Snapshot / Restore Management UI, dynamically updatable synonyms, and so much more. <a href="/blog/elasticsearch-7-3-0-released">Read all about it in the Elasticsearch release blog</a>.
	</li>
	<li>Kibana brings support for Kerberos, autocomplete and KQL support to filter aggregations, and Canvas workpad templates to make building beautiful displays easier — <a href="/blog/kibana-7-3-0-released">but that’s not all</a>.
	</li>
	<li>Beats adds support for a bunch of new data sources, including relational databases like Oracle and Amazon RDS, metrics for Kubernetes kube-proxy, kube-scheduler and kube-controller-manager, Network Flow support for GCP VPC Flow Logs, and improved support for Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Amazon Cloudwatch with Functionbeat. <a href="/blog/beats-7-3-0-released">Learn more in our Beats release blog</a>.
	</li>
	<li>Logstash now includes <a href="/blog/logstash-7-3-0-released">JMS support by default</a>.
	</li>
	<li>The Elastic APM .NET Agent is now generally available. Plus, Elastic APM adds a new way to view services with aggregate service breakdown charts, agent sample rate configuration right from Kibana, and a <a href="/blog/elastic-apm-7-3-0-released">whole lot more</a>.
	</li>
	<li>Elastic Uptime has improved the look and feel of multi-location monitors with <a href="/blog/elastic-uptime-monitoring-7-3-0-released">monitor summaries and details</a>.
	</li>
	<li>Elastic Logs adds <a href="/blog/elastic-logs-7-3-0-released">keyword highlighting</a>, along with the ability to jump to APM traces based on <code>trace.id</code>.</li>
	<li>Metrics Explorer in the Elastic Infrastructure app, which allows you to quickly perform aggregation visualizations against time-series metrics, is now ready for use in production systems. Elastic Infrastructure also adds improved monitoring of additional core Kubernetes services and a new RDS metricset in the AWS module. Learn more in <a href="/blog/elastic-infrastructure-7-3-0-released">the Elastic Infrastructure release blog</a>.</li>
</ul><p>Enjoy!
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-stack-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-stack-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve Kearns]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elasticsearch 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Today we are pleased to announce the release of Elasticsearch 7.3.0, based on Lucene 8.1.0. This is the latest stable release, and is already available for deployment via our <a href="/products/elasticsearch/service">Elasticsearch Service</a>.
</p><p>
	Latest stable release in 7.x:
</p><ul>
	<li><a href="/downloads/elasticsearch">Download Elasticsearch 7.3.0</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/release-notes-7.3.0.html">Elasticsearch 7.3.0 release notes</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/breaking-changes.html">Elasticsearch 7.3 breaking changes</a></li>
</ul><p>You can read about all the changes in the release notes linked above, but let's take a look at a few changes worth highlighting.
</p><h2>Data frames — transform and pivot your streaming data</h2><p>Data frame transforms are a core new feature in Elasticsearch that enable you to transform an existing index to a secondary, summarized index. <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/data-frame-apis.html">Data frame transforms</a> enable you to pivot your data and create entity-centric indices that can summarize the behavior of an entity. This organizes the data into an analysis-friendly format.
</p><p>Data frame transforms were originally available in 7.2. With 7.3 they can now run either as a single batch transform or continuously incorporating new data as it is ingested.
</p><p>Imagine you are streaming audit logs events from the many different hosts you have in your data center, and you want to analyze user behavior to find anything that looks suspicious. With data frames you can group the logs events by user, by host, and by day of the week. So for each user you have a count of interactions per server grouped by type of request. Organizing the data by entities and summarizing many events makes it easier to run different numerical analysis models and spot unusual behaviors.
</p><p>Data frames allow for new possibilities of machine learning analysis (such as outlier detection, which could be a perfect match for the above security example), but they can be useful for other types of visualisations or custom types of analysis. We are curious to see what users are up to using this feature.
</p><p>Data frame transforms is released as beta under a free Basic license.
</p><h2>Giving search a boost</h2><p>Elasticsearch is for search, and here are some exciting new search features we're releasing with 7.3.
</p><h3>Discover the least-frequent values</h3><p>We’ve added an all new <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/search-aggregations-bucket-rare-terms-aggregation.html"><code>rare_terms</code> aggregation</a>, which uses a resource efficient algorithm with predictable results. It is an aggregation designed to identify the long-tail of keywords, such as terms that have low doc counts. From a technical perspective, rare terms aggregation works by maintaining a map of terms with a counter associated with each value. The counter is incremented each time the term is identified. If the counter surpasses a predefined threshold, the term is removed from the map and inserted into a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuckoo_filter">cuckoo filter</a>. If a future term is found in the cuckoo filter, we assume it was previously removed from the map and is "common." This aggregation is designed to be more memory efficient than the alternative, which is setting a terms aggregation to <code>size: MAX_LONG</code>, or ordering a terms aggregation by count ascending, <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/search-aggregations-bucket-terms-aggregation.html#search-aggregations-bucket-terms-aggregation-order">in which errors are unbounded</a>.
</p><p>There are multiple use cases for rare terms aggregation; for example, <a href="/products/siem">SIEM</a> users are frequently interested in rare occurrences, which are sometimes suspected to be a manifestation of a security event.
</p><h3>Built-in vector similarity functions for document script scoring</h3><p>There are many popular algorithms that represent records by vectors (such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Word2vec">word2vec</a> and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolutional_neural_network">convolutional neural networks</a>), which allow relating to vector similarity as a measurement for record similarity. In this release we added <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/query-dsl-script-score-query.html#vector-functions">two predefined functions</a> to use for calculating vector similarity between a given query vector and document vectors:
</p><ul>
	<li>Cosine similarity</li>
	<li>Dot product similarity</li>
</ul><p>These are the two types of distance functions most frequently used in vector comparisons. We released these as Painless script functions, so users have full flexibility to use them in relevance ranking in combination with other fields. Users can use these Painless functions for scoring through the <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/query-dsl-script-score-query.html"><code>script_score</code></a> query. We plan to release additional vector similarity functions such as Euclidean distance and Manhattan distance in future releases, because each of these vector similarity functions proved superior for specific scenarios.
</p><p>Some of our users are using Elasticsearch as the data source for their machine learning algorithms, and have been requesting such functionality. We are thrilled to see what novel use the community will now find for Elasticsearch with the introduction of this capability.
</p><p>This experimental functionality is released under a free Basic license.
</p><h3>Improved intervals query</h3><p>In 7.0 we introduced the <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/query-dsl-intervals-query.html">intervals query</a>. This query is used when users want to find records in which words or phrases are within a certain distance from each other. It provides advanced search options in an easy-to-define syntax and yields accurate results.
</p><p>The intervals query is great for use cases such as legal and patent searches. Version 7.3 includes two important additions to intervals queries:
</p><ul>
	<li>The <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/query-dsl-intervals-query.html#intervals-wildcard"><code>wildcard</code> rule</a> within an intervals query allows for relating to a set of terms defined with a wildcard (* and ?), as well as choosing the analyzer that will be used.</li>
	<li>The <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/query-dsl-intervals-query.html#intervals-prefix"><code>prefix</code> rule</a> allows for defining intervals between terms that start with specific letters, with the option to <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/index-prefixes.html">index specifically for prefix </a>or to limit the query expansion to 128 alternative terms.</li>
</ul><p>Now that intervals queries are nearing feature parity with span queries, users can switch to intervals queries for the likes of legal and patent search.
</p><h3>Efficiently handle records with large number of dynamic fields</h3><p>The new <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/flattened.html">flattened object field</a>  will allow an entire flat JSON object to be indexed into a single field. This comes in handy for situations in which documents include a very large number of fields, such as HTTP headers or image metadata. Sub-fields of flattened objects behave almost exactly like keyword fields, so only basic queries and aggregations are allowed (no support for numeric range queries, full-text search, or highlighting). Prior to 7.3, records with a large number of fields had to be indexed into separate fields, which can greatly increase the number of mappings, making mappings more difficult to manage and increasing the size of the cluster state.
</p><p>Support for flattened object types is released under a free Basic license.
</p><h3>Update index synonyms list without index downtime</h3><p>With this feature, synonym filters used by <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/search-analyzer.html">search analyzers</a> can be updated quickly and flexibly. For example, e-commerce businesses can add new synonyms flexibly to verify that new products are associated with users’ queries, and do not return empty result sets. With the new <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/indices-reload-analyzers.html">Reload Search Analyzers</a> API, updating synonym filters only requires placing the file on the node and calling the Reload Search Analyzers API, which loads the search analyzers without restarting the index shards. This enables a user to update the synonyms per index without search and indexing downtime (index close and reopen).
</p><p>This experimental feature is released under a free Basic license.
</p><h2>Hold on, we have more cool stuff</h2><p>
	7.3 isn't just about improved search functionality, it also includes plenty of other new niceties.
</p><h3>A new type of master node just registered to vote</h3><p>Elasticsearch 7.0 introduced a <a href="/blog/a-new-era-for-cluster-coordination-in-elasticsearch">new cluster coordination layer</a>, with a number of improvements, including faster master elections, removal of the minimum_master_nodes setting, and use of <a href="/elasticon/conf/2018/sf/reliable-by-design-applying-formal-methods-to-distributed-systems">formal methods for design validation</a>. There was another important benefit to the new cluster coordination layer in Elasticsearch 7.0: It could be used as a foundation for important improvements in Elasticsearch, such as voting-only master-eligible nodes. A voting-only master-eligible node is a node that can participate in master elections but will not act as a master in the cluster (it only votes in elections). By only voting in elections, a smaller machine can be used, and fewer hardware resources are required for the cluster. Head over to the Elasticsearch docs for <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/modules-node.html#voting-only-node">instructions on setting up a voting-only master-eligible node</a> in Elasticsearch 7.3.
</p><p>Voting-only master-eligible nodes are available under a free Basic license.
</p><h3>Aliases can travel cross cluster</h3><p>Cross-cluster replication (CCR) was released as a <a href="/blog/elasticsearch-6-7-0-released">GA feature in Elasticsearch 6.7</a>. CCR has a variety of use cases, including <a href="/blog/cross-datacenter-replication-with-elasticsearch-cross-cluster-replication">cross-datacenter and cross-region replication</a>, replicating data to get closer to the application server and user, and maintaining a centralized reporting cluster replicated from a large number of smaller clusters. Elasticsearch 7.3 includes additional CCR functionality to ensure aliases that are manipulated on leader indices are replicated to the follower indices. Note: this process ignores <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/indices-aliases.html#aliases-write-index">write aliases</a> because follower indices do not receive direct writes, so write aliases have no use.
</p><h3>SQL query support for frozen indices for API clients and JDBC/ODBC drivers</h3><p>This feature allows for <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/sql-index-frozen.html">querying of frozen</a> indices through dedicated <a href="/webinars/introduction-to-elasticsearch-sql">SQL grammar extension</a>. Frozen indices are a super efficient way to keep older data that is not frequently searched, and doing that at low cost. Because users frequently will refrain from including frozen indices in their “normal” queries, when using SQL you need to explicitly request to include frozen indices. This can be done by using the FROZEN reserved word, such as <code>SELECT * FROM FROZEN myIndex LIMIT 10;</code>.
</p><h3>GUI support for snapshot restore and deletion</h3><p>Elasticsearch management UI (Kibana &gt; Management &gt; Elasticsearch) keeps evolving. In this version we enhanced the previously released <a href="/blog/elasticsearch-7-2-0-released">Snapshot Repositories section</a>, now called Snapshot and Restore, with the ability to restore from an existing snapshot. The snapshot restore wizard walks you through defining a restore task. The progress of currently running restores can be tracked in the Restore Status view. Snapshot deletion is also now available from the UI. For more information about these enhancements, see <a href="/guide/en/kibana/7.3/snapshot-repositories.html">Snapshot and Restore</a>.
</p><p>This UI functionality is released under a free Basic license.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt5830fc372cacbead/5d3a1da3ef4fb0543504c330/ES-7-3-release-snapshot--restore-blog.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt5830fc372cacbead" alt="Snapshot and Restore UI" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><h3>Discover your most unusual data using outlier detection</h3><p>The goal of <a href="/guide/en/elastic-stack-overview/7.3/dfa-outlier-detection.html">outlier detection</a> is to find the most unusual data points in an index. We analyze the numerical fields of each data point (document in an index) and annotate them with how unusual they are.
</p><p>We use unsupervised outlier detection, which means there is no need to provide a training data set to teach outlier detection to recognize outliers. In practice, this is achieved by using an ensemble of distance-based and density-based techniques to identify those data points that are the most different from the bulk of the data in the index. We assign to each analyzed data point an outlier score, which captures how different the entity is from other entities in the index.
</p><p>In addition to new outlier detection functionality, we are introducing the <a href="/guide/en/elasticsearch/reference/7.3/evaluate-dfanalytics.html">Evaluate API</a>, which enables users to compute a range of performance metrics such as confusion matrices, precision, recall, the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Receiver_operating_characteristic">receiver-operating characteristics (ROC) curve</a>, and the area under the ROC curve. If you are running outlier detection on a source index that has already been labeled to indicate which points are truly outliers and which are normal, you can use the Evaluate API to assess the performance of the outlier detection analytics on your dataset.
</p><p>This experimental feature is released under a Platinum license.
</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Please <a href="/downloads/elasticsearch">download Elasticsearch 7.3.0</a>, try it out, and let us know what you think on Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/elastic">@elastic</a>) or in our <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/">Discuss forums</a>. You can report any problems on the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/elasticsearch/issues">GitHub issues page</a>.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elasticsearch-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Yaron Parasol]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Kibana 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Today we are pleased to announce the release of Kibana 7.3.0. From Elastic Maps becoming production ready to Kerberos support and many more Kibana improvements, 7.3 is jam packed with Kibana goodness.
</p><p>Latest stable release in 7.3.0:
</p><ul>
	<li><a href="/downloads/kibana">Download Kibana 7.3.0</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/kibana/7.3/release-notes-7.3.0.html">Kibana 7.3.0 release notes</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/elastic-stack/7.3/kibana-breaking-changes.html">Kibana 7.3.0 breaking changes</a></li>
</ul><p>You can read about all the changes in the release notes linked above, but here are a few changes that are worth highlighting.
</p><h2>Elastic Maps is now GA!</h2><p>We’re excited to announce that Elastic Maps is production ready in 7.3. To find out more about what’s in Maps and how to use it, check out our <a href="/blog/elastic-maps-7-3-0-released">Maps 7.3.0 release announcement</a> and our <a href="/guide/en/kibana/master/maps.html">documentation</a>.
</p><p>The 7.3 release adds new layer styling enhancements, including the ability to select the color ramp for heatmap layers and to symbolize point features with icons that you can color, size, and rotate based on property values.
</p><p>Maps also includes a new top hits aggregation feature, which enables you to plot the most recent entities from your Elasticsearch indices.
</p><p>Another notable Maps improvement is that it’s now easier to get your geospatial data into the Elastic Stack. Use the new GeoJSON upload (beta) feature to drag and drop your points, shape files, and features and ingest them directly into Elasticsearch.
</p><p>Tooltips are enhanced to display a count of features at the current location. Pagination controls give you the ability to cycle through all features and view their properties. You can now provide custom labels for grid aggregation metrics and join metrics to provide better context in tooltips.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltcbb0ca03c4043404/5d3f57bf2550a26a5bd0aa52/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image1.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="bltcbb0ca03c4043404" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image1.gif">
</p><h2>Kerberos support</h2><p>Kerberos was supported in Elasticsearch starting in 6.6, and in 7.3, Kibana introduces the Kerberos authentication provider. This provides single-sign-on (SSO) access to users and the ability to log into Kibana without repeatedly providing a username and password.
</p><p>Kerberos is one of the oldest authentication protocols and one of the most heavily used in enterprise environments, supported both in Windows and Unix-based infrastructures. As a result, it is one of the most thoroughly tested protocols. SPNEGO is used in order to negotiate and implement the Kerberos protocol for web applications, i.e., to extend it to HTTP. Kerberos takes its name from the three-headed dog in Greek mythology that guarded the gates of the Underworld so the dead could not escape.
</p><p>The high-level idea is that the client and the server each share a secret with the Kerberos Distribution Center (KDC), which is a trusted authentication entity. When the client requests a service, it authenticates with Kerberos and obtains a ticket to the service. The password never travels; rather, it is used to produce a key. The hashed key, instead of the password, is then sent to the Kerberos Authentication Service (AS). Kerberos checks for the particular user in its database, hashes the corresponding password in turn (already existing in its database), and attempts to match it to the key it received through this login attempt. If successful, it grants a ticket.
</p><p>The ticket is encrypted with the secret, which is only shared between Kerberos and the service. The client then forwards the ticket to the service, which now knows that the client has authenticated with Kerberos, since it is providing a ticket encrypted with a secret only known to itself and KDC. In an SSO environment the ticket can then be shared with other services so that the user does not need to authenticate separately for each service they need to access. Hence, depending on your set up, Kibana might be retrieving the Kerberos ticket obtained initially for other services, without asking the user to log in. Once obtained, Kibana will next forward the ticket to Elasticsearch. In return it will receive an access and refresh token for subsequent Kibana/Elasticsearch comms. The following diagram is a simplification of the protocol.
</p><p style="text-align: center;"><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt252fc6f4a5d4f8ee/5d3f57e3e6078e234ba9df9f/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image2.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt252fc6f4a5d4f8ee" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image2.png">
</p><p>If you would like more details, please read up in our <a href="/guide/en/kibana/current/kibana-authentication.html#saml">Kibana Docs</a>.
</p><h2>Delete and restore snapshots</h2><p>The second phase of the snapshot management UI includes two notable enhancements: delete and restore. Delete snapshots to free up your repository storage space. To recover data and state from a snapshot, use the new Restore wizard.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt537bc7186be0b0e6/5d3f57f32ec4932346e0b250/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image3.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt537bc7186be0b0e6" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image3.png">
</p><h2>CSV export from a saved search
</h2><p>Kibana now allows you to export a saved search on a dashboard directly to CSV. This action is available in the dashboard panel menu for the saved search. To enable this feature, you must set <code>xpack.reporting.csv.enablePanelActionDownload: true</code> in your <code>kibana.yml</code> file.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt6974996db3a3cbb2/5d3f58003005926a604bb10f/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image4.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt6974996db3a3cbb2" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image4.png">
</p><h2>SIEM & ML: Better together
</h2><p>Users looking to extend their coverage beyond the prebuilt SIEM jobs can easily add custom anomaly detection jobs using the Machine Learning app. Detected anomalies are displayed on the Hosts and Network views in the SIEM app in an Anomalies table, and specific details are available in the Host Details and IP Details pages. Check out even more details about our SIEM solution in the <a href="/blog/elastic-siem-7-3-0-released">SIEM release blog</a>.
</p><h2>APM Service Breakdown Charts
</h2><p>The APM app adds a great new "Time spent by type" chart which allows you to see exactly where your applications are spending their time, allowing you to quickly identify and fix issues.  The service breakdown chart is visible on both per-service and per-transaction screens for the supported agent types.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt3eb2c5a47f3c1dc7/5d3f580c7aa78925d4429bc6/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image5.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt3eb2c5a47f3c1dc7" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image5.png">
</p><p>Read about this and other Observability changes, such as APM Agent Configuration, .NET Agent GA, Metrics Explorer GA, and more in our <a href="/blog/elastic-apm-7-3-0-released">APM</a>, <a href="/blog/elastic-infrastructure-7-3-0-released">Infrastructure</a>, <a href="/blog/elastic-logs-7-3-0-released">Logs</a>, and <a href="/blog/elastic-uptime-monitoring-7-3-0-released">Uptime</a> 7.3 blogs.
</p><h2>Show values inside bar charts
</h2><p>Bar charts now have the ability to show the values directly inside the chart, if space is available. When you create the bar chart, open <strong>Panel Settings</strong> and select <strong>Show values on chart</strong>.  A big thanks to Meir Meshi for contributing this feature.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt5ce524ed5b066cf4/5d3f581a3b58df25cf5c8efb/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image6.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt5ce524ed5b066cf4" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image6.png">
</p><h2>KQL + autocomplete in filter aggregation
</h2><p>KQL + autocomplete helps users write the queries they want without the need to memorize and learn syntax. In Kibana, we are now expanding this to filter aggregations. When users use filter aggregation in Visualize or TSVB, KQL is the default language and they can use the suggestions to write their query. KQL and autocomplete help users write queries using the right field names, operators, and values.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt24f02fa9e2aa9b18/5d3f582f3871f12662b33b16/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image7.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt24f02fa9e2aa9b18" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image7.gif">
</p><h2>Canvas updates
</h2><p>Canvas improves the user experience with new templates, experiences, and documentation.
</p><h3>Templates
</h3><p>Canvas is all about creating content and telling a story with your data. The content templates, or Canvases for short, help you facilitate this vision. In 7.3, Canvas releases three new templates: Summary, Pitch, and Status.
</p><ul>
	<li>The Summary template can help you create a report with live representations of your data.
	</li>
	<li>Pitch is a 14-page template that you can brand and customize for your next board-level presentation.
	</li>
	<li>The Status template gives you a solid, professional, and clean template for status reports and other updates.</li>
</ul><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt261f860cf17ef58e/5d3f58467aa78925d4429bd2/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image8.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt261f860cf17ef58e" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image8.png">
</p><h3>Experiences</h3><p>Canvas adds a number of experiences in 7.3: nudge, alignment, distribution, zoom, and fit to screen. Nudge enables you to more precisely align elements in your workpad. Use the up, down, left, or right arrow key to nudge an element by 10 pixels. Use Shift + an arrow key to nudge an element by 1 pixel.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltb161062cf495ae52/5d3f5874d97e9a23dcc4bdd0/kibana_7.3_release_blog_image9.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="bltb161062cf495ae52" alt="kibana_7.3_release_blog_image9.gif">
</p><h3>Documentation
</h3><p>Canvas has more documentation for you to peruse. Check out the updated <a href="/guide/en/kibana/master/canvas-getting-started.html">Getting started guide</a>, the new introduction to <a href="/guide/en/kibana/master/canvas-workpad.html">Canvas workpads</a>, and the improved <a href="/guide/en/kibana/master/canvas-function-reference.html">function reference</a>.
</p><h2>Conclusion
</h2><p>Kibana 7.3.0 is now available, and includes many more updates than listed above. We tried to pick a few select updates. Please read our <a href="/guide/en/kibana/7.3/release-notes-7.3.0.html">Kibana 7.3.0 release notes</a> for more information about the release. You can also <a href="/downloads/kibana">download Kibana 7.3.0</a>, try it out, and let us know what you think on Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/elastic">@elastic</a>), or in our <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/c/kibana">Kibana forums</a>. As you experience Kibana, you can report any problems on the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/kibana/issues">Kibana GitHub issues page</a>.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/kibana-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/kibana-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Shaun McGough]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Beats 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We’re pleased to announce the general availability of the Beats 7.3.0 release. This is the latest stable release and is now available for <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/beats">download</a>!
</p><p>This release is all about further growing the data source ecosystem!<span style="font-size: 12px;"></span></p><p><span style="font-size: 10px;"></span><br></p><h2>Automate Functionbeat with CloudFormation</h2><p><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/beats/functionbeat">Functionbeat</a> deploys on your serverless environment to collect events generated by cloud services and ship them over to Elasticsearch. The Functionbeat 7.3.0 release introduces the ability to export a CloudFormation template for integration with automation systems. Previously, Functionbeat was only available for manual command line deployment, but with this new functionality, users can now more easily automate Functionbeat deployments through their own CloudFormation stacks. We invite you to try out this new export feature and let us know what you think!
</p><p>CloudFormation templates can be exported with the <code>function</code> subcommand under the <code>export</code>&nbsp;command:</p><pre class="prettyprint">$ ./functionbeat export function &lt;FUNCTION_NAME&gt;
</pre><p><br></p><h2>Google Cloud integrations</h2><p><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/beats/filebeat">Filebeat 7.3.0</a> introduces a new <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.3/filebeat-module-googlecloud.html">Google Cloud module</a> that monitors Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) flow logs from Google Cloud through Stackdriver. It ships data to Elasticsearch in ECS format so it’s immediately available for analysis in the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/siem">SIEM app</a> (or with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/maps">Maps</a>, on a <a href="https://www.elastic.co/what-is/kibana-canvas">Canvas</a> workpad … you name it).</p><p>Along with the module, Filebeat also introduces a new <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.3/filebeat-input-google-pubsub.html">Google Pub/Sub input</a> for consuming from Google Pub/Sub topics. This input can be leveraged for centralized ingestion of all your events from Google Cloud for real-time analytics with the Elastic Stack.
</p><p><br></p><h2>Databases for days</h2><p>Databases are often the most critical part of a user-facing application. If they’re down or struggling, users are likely to notice the impact very quickly, so it’s important to understand how your database is performing. With the 7.3.0 release, we’re introducing support for three new databases in Metricbeat along with a new database source in Filebeat.
</p><h3>Oracle Database</h3><p>The new Metricbeat <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-oracle.html">Oracle module</a> provides the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-oracle-tablespace.html">tablespace</a> metricset, which includes information about data files and temp files, grouped by tablespace. This module includes information on used and free space, the status of the data files, as well as the status of the tablespace itself.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt145a107bbeaa2510/5d3f56c43871f12662b33b10/beats-7-3-0-metricbeat-oracle-dashboard-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt145a107bbeaa2510" alt="Metricbeat Oracle dashboard" "=""></p><h3>Amazon RDS</h3><p>If you’re using Amazon <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/">Relational Database Service (RDS)</a>, you can now collect a rich set of metrics about your deployment, from CPU and memory usage, to disk and network throughput and latency. See all the details in the new <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-aws-rds.html">RDS</a> metricset, now available in the Metricbeat <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-aws.html">AWS module</a>.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt0d6f1e7402e20a23/5d3f56dc2550a26a5bd0aa4c/beats-7-3-0-amazon-rds-dashboard-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt0d6f1e7402e20a23" alt="Metricbeat Amazon RDS dashboard" "=""></p><h3>CockroachDB</h3><p>The Metricbeat <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-cockroachdb.html">CockroachDB module</a> exposes the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-cockroachdb-status.html">status</a> metricset, which is compatible with any CockroachDB version exposing metrics in Prometheus format.</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt07584fd101cd47be/5d3f5705e6078e234ba9df97/beats-7-3-0-metricbeat-cockroach-dashboard-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt07584fd101cd47be" alt="Metricbeat CockroachDB dashboard" "=""></p><h3>Microsoft SQL Server
</h3><p>The new Filebeat <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.3/filebeat-module-mssql.html">MS SQL module</a> monitors the Microsoft SQL Server error logs with the Elastic Stack.
</p><p><br></p><h2>Improved Kubernetes monitoring</h2><p>Metricbeat 7.3.0 strengthens Kubernetes observability by introducing metricsets for three additional Kubernetes components:
</p><ul>
	<li>The <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-controllermanager.html">controllermanager</a> metricset captures metrics from <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/cloud-controller-manager/">kube-controller-manager</a>.</li>
	<li>The <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-proxy.html">proxy</a> metricset covers <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-proxy/">kube-proxy</a>, the network proxy component in Kubernetes.</li>
	<li>The <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-scheduler.html">scheduler</a> metricset provides visibility into the <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-scheduler/">kube-scheduler</a>.</li>
</ul><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt564aa21095c29a24/5d3f57222ec4932346e0b246/beats-7-3-0-metricbeat-kubernetes-dashboard-blog.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt564aa21095c29a24" alt="Metricbeat Kubernetes (k8s) data" "=""></p><p><br></p><h2>Configuration-only Metricbeat modules</h2><p>We’re always looking for ways to streamline the process of adding new supported data sources. That’s why 7.3.0 introduces a new way of creating Metricbeat modules that doesn’t require a single line of Go code. We’re calling them light modules and they’re effectively a pre-defined configuration on top of an existing, more generic module, such as <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-prometheus.html">Prometheus</a> or <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-jolokia.html">Jolokia</a>. In fact, the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-cockroachdb.html">CockroachDB</a> module introduced in this release is our first light module, and it was much easier to create as a result.
</p><p>Stay tuned — we’ll be sharing more about these light modules moving forward.
</p><p><br></p><h2>There’s a lot more to see
</h2><p>If you’ve made it this far, you might want to check out some of our related release blogs:
</p><ul>
	<li>The Elastic APM .NET Agent is now generally available. Plus, Elastic APM adds a new way to view services with aggregate service breakdown charts, agent sample rate configuration right from Kibana, and a <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-apm-7-3-0-released">whole lot more</a>.</li>
	<li>Elastic Uptime has improved the look and feel of multi-location monitors with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-uptime-monitoring-7-3-0-released">monitor summaries and details</a>.</li>
	<li>Elastic Logs adds <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-logs-7-3-0-released">keyword highlighting</a>, along with the ability to jump to APM traces based on <code>trace.id</code>.</li>
	<li>Metrics Explorer in the Elastic Infrastructure app, which allows you to quickly perform aggregation visualizations against time-series metrics, is now ready for use in production systems. Elastic Infrastructure also adds improved monitoring of additional core Kubernetes services and a new RDS metricset in the AWS module. Learn more in the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-infrastructure-7-3-0-released">Elastic Infrastructure release blog</a>.</li>
</ul><p>Please refer to the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/libbeat/7.3/release-notes-7.3.0.html">release notes</a> for the complete list of bug fixes and features.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/beats-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/beats-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alvin Chen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Logstash 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We’re happy to announce the general availability of the Logstash 7.3.0 release. This is the latest stable release and is now available for <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/logstash">download</a>!&nbsp; Please refer to the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/7.3/logstash-7-3-0.html">release notes</a>&nbsp;for the complete list of bug fixes and features.
</p><p><br></p><h2 style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">Pipeline-to-pipeline communication improvements</h2><p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">The <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/7.3/pipeline-to-pipeline.html">pipeline-to-pipeline communication</a> feature was introduced back in Logstash 6.3.0 as a new way to connect <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/7.3/multiple-pipelines.html">multiple pipelines</a> within the same Logstash instance. Historically,&nbsp;monolithic pipeline configurations were commonly used to construct sophisticated processing logic for handling the data flow of multiple different data sources. Today, configurations can be effectively split out into separate, isolated pipelines that are stitched together with pipeline-to-pipeline communication. This helps both streamline performance and enhance processing modularity.</p><p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);">With Logstash 7.3.0, we've made a notable effort to spruce up this feature and have <a href="https://github.com/elastic/logstash/issues/10502">resolved all known bugs</a>. Although still in beta, right now would be the perfect time to give it a spin. We look forward to any feedback you may have!</p><p style="background-color: rgb(255, 255, 255);"><br></p><h2>Consuming from JMS queues</h2><p>Java Message Service (JMS) technologies are an important part of some of our users’ production environments. In Logstash 7.2.0, we overhauled the Logstash <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/7.3/plugins-inputs-jms.html">JMS input plugin</a>, improving performance, security, and reliability. With the 7.3.0 release, we’re now bundling the JMS input plugin by default so its readily available as soon as you upgrade.
</p><p>The JMS input plugin supports consuming data from any JMS technology into the Elastic Stack by embracing the bring-your-own-driver model, similar to the JDBC plugins. We encourage you to try it out with your own JMS deployments and let us know what you think! Curious what this looks like in action? Glad you asked — <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/integrating-jms-with-elasticsearch-service-using-logstash">we have just the blog for you</a>.</p><p><br></p><h2>Feedback</h2><p>Please <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/logstash">download Logstash 7.3.0</a>, try it out, and let us know what you think on Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/elastic">@elastic</a>) or in our <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/">forums</a>. You can report any bugs or feature requests on the Logstash <a href="https://github.com/elastic/logstash/issues">Github issues page</a> or within the <a href="https://github.com/logstash-plugins">respective plugin repositories</a></p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/logstash-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/logstash-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alvin Chen]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic APM 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce a new release of Elastic APM, version 7.3.0, available on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a>, or as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of Elastic Stack. This release brings enhancements to the APM App UI, React support for single-page applications (SPA), and the highly anticipated .NET agent.
</p><h2>Elastic APM .NET Agent GA</h2><p>We are super pumped to announce that Elastic APM agent for .NET is now generally available! Thanks to all of you that provided us with valuable feedback on the preview and beta versions of the agent. The .NET Agent adds automatic instrumentation for ASP.NET Core 2.x+ and Entity Framework Core 2.x+, while also providing a <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/apm/agent/dotnet/current/public-api.html">Public API</a> for the .NET agent that will allow you to instrument any .NET custom application code. If you haven’t had the chance to check out the new agent, test drive the <a href="https://github.com/elastic/apm-agent-dotnet/">agent</a> and let us know what you would like to see <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfBjUbv9qjcwNFSXpjJT_PmGJn0kpuF1IdZDtnBl0MLNRbYbQ/viewform?usp=sf_link">added to it</a>.&nbsp;
</p><p><br></p><h2>Aggregate Service Breakdown Charts</h2><p>In addition to the transaction duration and throughput charts, 7.3 release adds aggregated service breakdown charts for services. These charts help you visualize where your application and services are spending most of their time, allowing you to get to the root cause of a performance problem quickly. These charts are available in Beta with support for certain APM agents(Java, Go, Node.js, Python).&nbsp;
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt81f63d0e7ef4d158/5d38643b5cb66453b127a1c2/image3.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt81f63d0e7ef4d158" alt="image3.png">
</p><p><br></p><h2>Agent Sample Rate Configuration from APM UI</h2><p>Configuring sampling rate for your services is&nbsp;a whole lot easier with this release. The new settings page now lets you view and configure the sampling rate for your services from within the APM UI without changing the agent yaml files for each individual reporting instance of the service. Check out our <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/kibana/7.3/agent-configuration.html">docs</a>&nbsp;to learn more about this configuration.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt9665b3b2de8a8106/5d38644fc3a6d753ac37b724/image4.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt9665b3b2de8a8106" alt="image4.png">
</p><p><br></p><h2>React support for Single Page Applications&nbsp;</h2><p>7.3 release also brings a lot of exciting changes to the RUM (Real User Monitoring) agent. We have furthered our support Single Page Applications. You can now use the RUM agent to instrument your SPA (Single Page applications) written in React.js without the need to manually create or rename transactions. &nbsp; Check out the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/apm/agent/js-base/current/react-integration.html">docs</a> and instrument your React SPA today!
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt2095fbbc02d32f8a/5d3864f72a506857d64f03ef/image1.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt2095fbbc02d32f8a" alt="image1.gif">
</p><p><br></p><h2>APM RUM integration with Elastic Maps</h2><p>We have also made both the geo-ip and user-agent modules enabled by default, making it easier for you to integrate with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/maps">Maps</a> so you can better understand the performance of your RUM applications.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt0783d82332ade3b8/5d38653cd5e2de4f5c29cc04/image2.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt0783d82332ade3b8" alt="image2.png">
</p><p><br>
</p><h2>Try it out!</h2><p>You can access the 7.3.0 Elastic APM application on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud, or you can download it as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of the Elastic Stack. Grab the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/apm">APM Server</a> (or leverage the one included with an Elasticsearch Service account), instrument your applications with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/apm/agent/index.html">APM agents</a>, and start monitoring your applications.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-apm-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-apm-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Neha Duggal]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic Maps is now generally available]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce that <a href="/products/maps">Elastic Maps</a> is now generally available and ready to take your geospatial analysis to the next layer. Launched in beta in version 6.7, Elastic Maps is a powerful Kibana application that opens up new ways to visually explore your location data available in Elasticsearch.
</p><p>Elastic Maps is included in the free, default distribution of the Elastic Stack, and users can experience it by either <a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service">spinning up a cluster in Elasticsearch Service on Elastic Cloud</a> or <a href="/downloads">downloading the Elastic Stack</a>.
</p><h2>Location data + search: A journey that goes way back </h2><p>Whether you’re monitoring the regional performance of your application with <a href="/products/apm">Elastic APM</a>, tracking the physical locations of suspicious IPs trying to breach your network through <a href="/products/siem">Elastic SIEM</a>, or using logs to <a href="/use-cases/delhivery">monitor the operational visibility of packages</a> in near real time, location data and search go hand in hand across many use cases.
</p><p>Our community has been using the Elastic Stack for their geospatial needs <a href="/blog/geo-location-and-search">since the beginning (version 0.9.1!</a>). Elasticsearch as a data store allows you to query large amounts of geo data — with relevance and speed — at scale. On the ingest side of things, both Beats and Logstash can quickly enrich your logs and metrics with geospatial information by automatically generating a physical location of an IP using the geoip processor. Kibana has always offered the ability to easily map location data and quickly correlate it with the rest of your data stored in Elasticsearch.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blta55b0643964d4b45/5d3789c25cb66453b1279c1c/02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-7-3-0.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blta55b0643964d4b45" alt="02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-7-3-0.png"><br>
</p><p>Over the years, Elastic has been investing heavily in our geospatial capabilities. We’ve significantly improved Elasticsearch query time, index time, storage densities, and memory utilization for geo data by modifying the underlying algorithms to use a new BKD tree structure. Elastic Maps is the natural step forward in that journey. Earlier this year, we <a href="/blog/elastic-maps-beta-released">launched a beta version</a> of Elastic Maps. We are excited to graduate Elastic Maps to general availability status in version 7.3.
</p><p>"Geospatial data is a key part of many of our use cases, and we have invested heavily in making it faster and easier over the years," said Shay Banon, founder and CEO of Elastic. "We're super excited to release Elastic Maps, a new solution that leverages our existing query capabilities and provides a more powerful, interactive, and customizable visualization layer, supporting multiple layers, zooming into individual documents, and more."
</p><h2>Your location data, alongside everything else </h2><p>From coordinates to countries, we treat location as just another data point. This is why we felt it was extremely important for maps created in the Elastic Maps app to be embeddable in a Kibana dashboard. As of 7.2, your highly customized and multi-layered map can be added to a Kibana dashboard just like any time series chart, word cloud, or saved search. Simply draw a shape on your map to filter down and correlate location with all other attributes in your data.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt34d3f56910e64aef/5d379d2cef4fb0543504b41b/02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-drilldown-7-3-0.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt34d3f56910e64aef" alt="02-elasticsearch-elastic-maps-suricata-events-drilldown-7-3-0.gif">
</p><h2>Classification, custom point icons, and last known location</h2><p>Since the beta, we have added several features that give users more control over the styling and interaction with their data in Elastic Maps.
</p><p><strong>Layer classification:</strong> Classify layers based on particular criteria to enable new capabilities like styling based on status (such as host uptime) or on thresholds (such as service response time).
</p><p><strong>Custom icons:</strong> Showcase points on a map with a variety of different icons wherein the size, color, and orientation can be statically or dynamically styled.
</p><p><strong>Last known location:</strong> For use cases that require tracking the most recent status, you can also opt in to show only the last known location for a given point on a layer using the Top Hits aggregation in Elasticsearch.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt2cae836aea7367f2/5d379d6ce76cd34ed38d690e/03-elasticsearch-kibana-elastic-maps-last-known-location-7-3-0.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt2cae836aea7367f2" alt="03-elasticsearch-kibana-elastic-maps-last-known-location-7-3-0.png"></p><h2>Upload features, shapes, and more from GeoJSON</h2><p>At Elastic, we strive to make our products simple and easy to use. Our GeoJSON upload feature, a new beta feature in Elastic Maps, is very much aligned with this theme. Through direct ingestion into Elasticsearch, the feature enables map creators to drag and drop GeoJSON files enriched with points, shapes, and content into a map for instantaneous visualization.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt2c726e71cc52926d/5d379d86e76cd34ed38d6914/04-elasticsearch-kibana-geojson-elastic-maps-7-3-0.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt2c726e71cc52926d" alt="04-elasticsearch-kibana-geojson-elastic-maps-7-3-0.gif"></p><p>And if you’re simply looking to add vector shapes for certain regions on a map, the <a href="/elastic-maps-service">Elastic Maps Service</a> continues to add more and more hosted regions to our library (<a href="https://maps.elastic.co/">explore here</a>) for an out-of-the-box experience.
</p><h2>Just getting started</h2><p>While this release is a huge milestone for Elastic Maps, we’re just getting started. We will continue to invest in more robust features across the stack that will take exploration of location-based data to new levels. Whether you’re already using the stack for popular use cases such as log analytics, security analytics, or observability, or are simply exploring options for your geospatial needs, Elastic Maps is a powerful tool for your location data analysis and exploration.
</p><h2>Try Elastic Maps today</h2><p>To get started, spin up a trial cluster on our <a href="/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> or install the latest version of the <a href="/downloads">Elastic Stack</a>. Already have data in Elasticsearch? Take Elastic Maps for a test drive with the latest version of the stack.
</p><p>We have some great material to get you started:
</p><ul>
	<li><a href="/products/maps">Elastic Maps solution page</a></li>
	<li><a href="/blog/elastic-maps-beta-released">Elastic Maps beta release blog</a></li>
	<li><a href="/webinars/elastic-maps-for-geospatial-analysis">Elastic Maps for Geospatial Analysis webinar</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/kibana/current/maps.html">Elastic Maps documentation</a></li>
</ul>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-maps-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-maps-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex Francoeur]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic SIEM 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/introducing-elastic-siem">introduced Elastic SIEM as a beta</a> in version 7.2, and we are already seeing strong adoption and receiving positive feedback from our community. Five weeks later, we’re here with version 7.3, and we have even more to share.</p>
<p>If you’d like to give Elastic SIEM a try, the 7.3 version is available on our <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service/signup">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud, and for download in the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/start">default distribution of the Elastic Stack</a>.</p>
<h3 id="improvedetectionwithintegratedmachinelearning">Improve detection with integrated machine learning</h3>
<p>For 7.3, we’ve integrated machine learning anomaly detection jobs into the SIEM app, streamlining security operations workflows and taking a meaningful step toward integrating detection rules into Elastic SIEM. </p>
<p>Anomaly detection is vital for effective threat detection and threat hunting because it addresses gaps left by traditional correlation-based alerting. In 7.3, users can easily enable and run a set of machine learning anomaly detection jobs to detect specific attack-related behaviors — right from the SIEM app. Users looking to extend their coverage beyond these prebuilt jobs can easily add custom anomaly detection jobs using the Machine Learning app.</p>
<p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt037f040e535f5a61/5d3b55d3ffcdbf4f57a78e0d/screenshot-siem-home-with-ml-jobs-1366x768.jpg" alt="enter image description here" /></p>
<p>Detected anomalies are displayed on the Hosts and Network views in the SIEM app and specific details are available in the Host Details and IP Details pages.</p>
<h3 id="viewunderlyingqueries">View underlying queries</h3>
<p>Analysts can now examine the queries that drive most of the chart and table widgets in the SIEM app. It’s as simple as accessing the Inspect button located in the top-right corner of these visualizations. This is our first step toward empowering practitioners to customize the SIEM app to support organizational workflows.</p>
<h3 id="ingestgcpvpcflowlogs">Ingest GCP VPC flow logs</h3>
<p>We’ve also introduced a Filebeat module that ingests Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) flow logs from Google Cloud. It ships data in Elastic Common Schema (ECS) format, of course, so events are available for immediate analysis in the SIEM app (or with Maps, on a Canvas workpad…you name it).</p>
<h3 id="getstartedtoday">Get started today</h3>
<p>Haven’t tried Elastic SIEM yet? Spin up a cluster on our <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> or <a href="http://www.elastic.co/downloads">install the latest version</a> of the Elastic Stack. Already have ECS data in Elasticsearch? Just upgrade your clusters to 7.3 and give Elastic SIEM a try. </p>
<p>To simplify your getting started journey, we have some great material to get you started: </p>
<ul>
<li><p>Elastic SIEM solutions page: https://www.elastic.co/solutions/siem</p></li>
<li><p>Elastic SIEM documentation: https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/siem/guide/current/index.html</p></li>
<li><p>Elastic SIEM webinar recording: https://www.elastic.co/webinars/introducing-elastic-siem </p></li>
</ul>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-siem-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-siem-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Paquette]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic Logs 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce a new release of Elastic Logs, version 7.3.0, available on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a>, or as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of Elastic Stack. This release brings additional workflow tools, like ad-hoc keyword highlighting, and trace-level integration between Logs and APM UIs! </p> <h2>Ad hoc keyword highlighting</h2> <p>When you look at a massive amount of logs, sometimes it’s hard to pick out specific details. Ever tried to scan logs scrolling past you for the word “error”? Now, you can easily do that, with some help from ad-hoc keyword highlights you define! Happy hunting ;)</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt13f3d43dfccfa2b0/5d385775ef4fb0543504b777/logs-highlighting.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt13f3d43dfccfa2b0" alt="logs-highlighting.gif"></p> <h2>Integration between Logs and APM</h2> <p>Many log messages get printed from the same applications that are instrumented by Elastic APM. If you are using a supported logging framework, your log messages will be automatically decorated with the trace.id field. This integration allows you to automatically navigate from a specific log event to APM traces, while preserving trace context.&nbsp; </p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt904b270ac5a13cee/5d3857025cb66453b127a0c8/image2.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt904b270ac5a13cee" alt="image2.png"></p> <h2>See it in action!</h2> <p>You access the latest version of the Elastic Logs application on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud by creating a new cluster, or upgrading an existing cluster the day of release, or you can download it as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of the Elastic Stack. </p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-logs-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-logs-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Tanya Bragin]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic Infrastructure 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce a new release of Elastic Infrastructure, version 7.3.0, available on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a>, or as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of Elastic Stack. This release brings the much-awaited GA version of Metrics Explorer - a quick and easy way to explore infrastructure metrics, lot’s of new integrations and improvements to the existing ones.
</p><h2>Metrics Explorer GA</h2><p>We are excited to announce general availability of Metrics Explorer in Elastic 7.3!
</p><p>Metrics are key indicators of infrastructure’s health, and for any sizeable infrastructure there are a lot of them. Our main goal with Metrics Explorer was to make browsing and analyzing metrics a smooth experience.&nbsp;
</p><p>By default, Metrics Explorer shows the CPU information for all infrastructure assets, such as hosts, Kubernetes pods, and containers. This can easily be broken down per entity, such as container name, by selecting the respective field in the "graph per" section. Any graph can be opened in Time Series Visual Builder (TSVB), where it can be further enhanced, annotated, and published on a dashboard. In addition, you can quickly switch to the host overview from each graph’s action menu.&nbsp;
</p><p>Simple, right? That’s the goal of Metrics Explorer -- simple and fast visualization experience regardless of the underlying complexity.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltbf91018c2ea0cee9/5d385fd5c044d1543ab0a9c2/image4.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="bltbf91018c2ea0cee9" alt="image4.gif">
</p><p>Hitting the general availability milestone means that starting from 7.3 Metrics Explorer can be used in production systems. That’s just the beginning! We are going to continue evolving and improving Metrics Explorer and other parts of Elastic Infrastructure. Let us know what you think. Ask a question or leave feedback in our <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/">forums</a>.
</p><h2>Improved Kubernetes monitoring</h2><p>In our previous <a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-observability-update-7-2-0">blog post</a> we talked about our commitment to supporting dynamic environments based on Kubernetes. In this release, we continue expanding our integrations with cloud-native technologies by adding new modules and improving the existing ones.&nbsp;
</p><p>Release 7.3 strengthens Kubernetes observability by introducing metricsets for three Kubernetes components:
</p><ul>
	<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-controllermanager.html">controllermanager</a> captures metrics from <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/cloud-controller-manager/">kube-controller-manager</a></li>
	<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-proxy.html">proxy</a> covers <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-proxy/">kube-proxy</a>, the network proxy component in Kubernetes</li>
	<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-kubernetes-scheduler.html">scheduler</a> provides visibility into the <a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/command-line-tools-reference/kube-scheduler/">kube-scheduler</a></li>
</ul><p>The updated Kubernetes module ships with expanded overview dashboards for the new metricsets.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt1ac578f86d04d71c/5d385fedc3a6d753ac37b70e/image1.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt1ac578f86d04d71c" alt="image1.gif" "="">
</p><figcaption>Kubernetes Dashboard</figcaption><h2>AWS RDS monitoring</h2><p>The AWS module got an enhancement as well - the new <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-metricset-aws-rds.html">rds metricset</a> collects data from Amazon's<a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/"> Relational Database Service (RDS)</a>&nbsp; service in all regions.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltf1ff02cea907bc4c/5d386064d5e2de4f5c29cbda/image3.png" data-sys-asset-uid="bltf1ff02cea907bc4c" alt="image3.png">
</p><figcaption>AWS RDS Overview Dashboard</figcaption><h2>Oracle database monitoring</h2><p>The latest addition to our list of database integrations is the new <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-oracle.html">Oracle module</a> that collects metrics from the Oracle Database Servers. Currently it includes the Tablespace metricset, which&nbsp;
</p><p>includes information about data files and temp files, grouped by Tablespace.&nbsp; This beta module includes information on used and free space, the status of the data files, as well as the status of the Tablespace itself.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt9cacb1ded5e13137/5d3860dfc3a6d753ac37b714/image2.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt9cacb1ded5e13137" alt="image2.png">
</p><figcaption>Oracle Dashboard</figcaption><h2>Configuration-only Metricbeat modules</h2><p>In this release we introduced a new way of creating Metricbeat modules that doesn’t require writing a single line of Go code. These so called light modules can be derived from the existing modules, such as <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-prometheus.html">Prometheus</a> or <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-jolokia.html">Jolokia</a>. Think of them as predefined configurations of the more generic metricsets. The main goal with light modules is to make it simple to integrate with services whose protocols we already support. We will be publishing more information on light modules, stay tuned.
</p><p>The first light module we realized in 7.3 was for CockroachDB - the distributed SQL database. The <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.3/metricbeat-module-cockroachdb.html">CockroachDB module</a> is derived from the Prometheus module and exposes the status metricset, which is compatible with any CockroachDB version exposing metrics in Prometheus format.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt3daa27c29c47ee70/5d38614a5cb66453b127a1a2/image5.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt3daa27c29c47ee70" alt="image5.png">
</p><figcaption>CockroachDB Dashboard</figcaption><h2>See it in action!</h2><p>You can access the latest version of the Elastic Infrastructure application on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud by creating a new cluster, or upgrading an existing cluster the day of release, or you can download it as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of the Elastic Stack.&nbsp;
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-infrastructure-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-infrastructure-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dimitri Mazmanov]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Elastic Uptime Monitoring 7.3.0 released]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce a new release of Elastic Uptime Monitoring, version 7.3.0, available on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a>, or as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of Elastic Stack.
</p><h2>Monitor Summaries</h2><p>When it comes to monitoring applications with Uptime, users often set up several geographically-dispersed monitors to get multiple perspectives on user experience.&nbsp;
</p><p>Monitor Summaries allow the user to see multiple Heartbeat results grouped in a single, expandable row per monitored endpoint. This visual representation in Uptime UI, called "Monitor summaries" improves the experience for users that are using multiple Heartbeat instances.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt23802e655f0d4614/5d386ae2e76cd34ed38d6e09/image2.gif" data-sys-asset-uid="blt23802e655f0d4614" alt="image2.gif">
</p><figcaption>Collapsable summaries<br><br><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt962f9f0af43026d7/5d386b0ce228515753543dd3/image3.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt962f9f0af43026d7" alt="image3.png"></figcaption><p> In a closer look, as we expand a single endpoint, we can see the status of this endpoint monitored from 3 locations (California, New York, and the UK, which is currently down).
</p><h3>Monitors page</h3><p>Several UI improvements were made to the Monitors detail screen. The most significant one is the "Monitor duration" chart, where the user can see the duration of a single endpoint check across multiple locations, with the additional ability to filter per location as needed.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt5f01b5078e5082a8/5d386b22ffcdbf4f57a77af8/image1.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blt5f01b5078e5082a8" alt="image1.png"></p><h2>Want to see it in action?</h2><p>You can access the 7.3.0 Elastic Uptime application on the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud, or you can download it as part of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">default distribution</a> of the Elastic Stack. Download <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/beats/heartbeat">Heartbeat</a>, follow the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/heartbeat/current/heartbeat-getting-started.html">instructions</a> on how to set it up, and start monitoring your applications and services today.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-uptime-monitoring-7-3-0-released</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/elastic-uptime-monitoring-7-3-0-released</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Dov Hershkovitch]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Observability on blockchain and the Hyperledger project]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/hyperledger/fabric#releases">Hyperledger Fabric</a> is a blockchain framework by the Linux Foundation that uses some open source projects to build a modular blockchain application. And do you know what? You can monitor your Hyperledger Fabric applications with the Elastic Stack. :)
</p><p>We are going to assume a specific Hyperledger Fabric setup. With Hyperledger Fabric you can deploy your application using different "blocks" to achieve the same result. For example, you can use a Hyperledger Fabric internal implementation, Kafka, or <a href="https://github.com/etcd-io/etcd">etcd</a> for consensus operations, and you can use GoLevelDB or CouchDB as database.
</p><p>The services deployed for this example are:
</p><ul>
	<li>Apache Kafka for ordering, monitored with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-kafka.html">Metricbeat Kafka module</a></li>
	<li>Apache Zookeeper as a requirement of Apache Kafka, monitored with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-zookeeper.html">Metricbeat Zookeeper module</a></li>
	<li>CouchDB as the source of truth database, monitored with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-couchdb.html">Metricbeat CouchDB module</a></li>
	<li>Peers monitored with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-prometheus.html">Metricbeat Prometheus module</a></li>
	<li>Orderer service written in Go, monitored with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-golang.html">Metricbeat Golang module</a></li>
</ul><p>The result is a very rich dashboard with an overall view of a Hyperledger Fabric network:
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt0c455b80c85170db/5d3e0f08165116375f8ad5e0/hyperledger-observability-overall-dashboard-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt0c455b80c85170db" alt="Dashboard with overall view" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p>In the screenshot above we see a portion of a dashboard specifically built for Hyperledger Fabric. We can also see Metricbeat, Filebeat, and Heartbeat working in harmony. Each peer inside the Hyperledger Fabric network is monitored by configuring them to expose Prometheus metrics. <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/heartbeat/7.2/heartbeat-getting-started.html">Heartbeat</a> is also used; in this case, Heartbeat supports ICMP, TCP, and HTTP protocols so we have configured it to monitor all HTTP endpoints that were available.
</p><p>The network is deployed in Docker so the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/metricbeat-module-docker.html">Metricbeat Docker module</a> has been configured to monitor it. But also, a Filebeat configured with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.2/filebeat-input-container.html">Container as input</a> (previously called Docker input) and with the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/metricbeat/7.2/add-docker-metadata.html">add_docker_metadata</a> processor allow us to extract and enrich Docker generated logs. Because we are not using any Filebeat module to process Docker log lines, the configuration can’t be simpler:
</p><pre class="prettyprint">filebeat.inputs:
  - type: container
    enabled: true
    paths:
      - /path_to_your_docker_logs/*/*.log
    json.keys_under_root: true
output.elasticsearch:
  hosts: ["your_elasticsearch:9200"]
processors:
  - add_host_metadata: ~
  - add_docker_metadata:
      host: "unix:///var/run/docker.sock"
</pre><p>The config above points the container input in Filebeat to the logs path (in this case, they were Docker containers so it points to the Docker logs path). Docker outputs log lines as JSON so we set to true <code>json.keys_under_root</code> so that they are not “stringified.” We configure our Elasticsearch cluster and add two very useful processors: <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.2/add-host-metadata.html">add_host_metadata</a>, which enriches the JSON with useful data coming from the host machine where Filebeat is running; and <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/beats/filebeat/7.2/add-docker-metadata.html">add_docker_metadata</a> which, in turn, enriches the JSON with useful information about the Docker engine that is running the containers.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltc0b18b2bb3e8e634/5d3e0f32165116375f8ad5e6/hyperledger-observability-container-json-data-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="bltc0b18b2bb3e8e634" alt="JSON enriched with useful Docker data" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p>Apart from the Discover tab, you can also use the Logs UI to have a never-ending stream of logs with customized columns and data:
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt88ca3aff539e63e1/5d3e0f8965a8bf360426aea8/hyperledger-observability-logs-ui-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt88ca3aff539e63e1" alt="Logs UI with customized columns and data" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p>Finally, if logs, metrics, and uptime data playing together weren’t enough, you can also use the Infrastructure app. There you can see a different view of the infrastructure; in this case, we grouped the containers by image name to see their CPU usage.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltb54a114ddfb52861/5d3e0fcc1f1c20368b7349af/hyperledger-observability-infra-ui-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="bltb54a114ddfb52861" alt="Infrastructure UI with containers grouped by image name" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p>The Elastic Stack for observability is critical for any complex distributed system, but don't forget that you must also instrument your apps with Elastic APM solution to "close the circle" of observability inside your product: logs, metrics, uptime, and tracing.
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blte7cf30b41ea796bf/5d3e1015cc2cb63e6348cb4d/hyperledger-observability-apm-blog.png" data-sys-asset-uid="blte7cf30b41ea796bf" alt="APM dashboard showing transaction sample" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/blt17ddfa9b106db882/5d3e104527d09d3764c6df44/hyperledger-observability-apm-txns-blog.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="blt17ddfa9b106db882" alt="APM dashboard showing transaction graphs" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><p>Bonus! Did you know that Kibana now has dark mode? If you want to give it a try, just go to Management - Advanced Settings and activate it! :) Here we can see the Logs UI in dark mode:
</p><p><img src="https:/static-www.elastic.co/v3/assets/bltefdd0b53724fa2ce/bltbc31b85a4e1952cd/5d3e10a18d62573e6d6c6f15/hyperledger-observability-dark-mode.jpg" data-sys-asset-uid="bltbc31b85a4e1952cd" alt="Kibana in dark mode" style="display: block; margin: auto;">
</p><h2>Want to see it in action?</h2><p>You can start monitoring your Hyperledger Fabric today by signing up for a free trial of the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/cloud/elasticsearch-service">Elasticsearch Service</a> on Elastic Cloud, or you can <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/">download</a> it as part of the default distribution of the Elastic Stack. Grab the <a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/beats/metricbeat">Metricbeat</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.elastic.co/downloads/beats/filebeat">Filebeat</a> executables appropriate for your platform and start monitoring!
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/observability-on-blockchain-and-the-hyperledger-project</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/observability-on-blockchain-and-the-hyperledger-project</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Mario Castro]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Announcing Elastic Cloud on Kubernetes (ECK) 0.9.0 Alpha 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Today we are happy to announce the release of Elastic Cloud on Kubernetes (ECK) 0.9.0. This is the second pre-release version of ECK, which is built for managing Elasticsearch and Kibana on Kubernetes. We encourage you to try ECK out and give us feedback through our <a href="https://discuss.elastic.co/c/eck">Discuss forum</a> or through our <a href="https://github.com/elastic/cloud-on-k8s/">GitHub repository</a>.
</p><table style="background: #FFFFD2;">
<tbody>
<tr>
	<td><strong>IMPORTANT:</strong> This is an alpha release and is intended for testing purposes only. Do not deploy in production.
	</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table><ul>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/cloud-on-k8s/0.9/k8s-quickstart.html">Deploy ECK 0.9.0</a></li>
	<li><a href="/guide/en/cloud-on-k8s/0.9/k8s-release-notes.html">Release notes</a></li>
</ul><p>The release notes give an overview of all that has changed from the first release.
</p><p>Here are the highlights of this release:
</p><h2>Elastic Cloud on (more) Kubernetes</h2><p>Our goal for ECK is to be the best experience for running the Elastic Stack on Kubernetes. We understand many of our users might be making use of vanilla Kubernetes, one provided by their cloud provider, or an enterprise-focused version. The initial alpha version supported Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) and vanilla Kubernetes version 1.11 and up. With ECK 0.9.0 we’ve extended this to the following distributions:
</p><ul>
	<li>Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE)</li>
	<li>Red Hat OpenShift 3.11+</li>
	<li>Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)</li>
	<li>Amazon Container Service for Kubernetes (EKS)</li>
	<li>Vanilla Kubernetes</li>
</ul><h2>Elastic APM Server enters ECK</h2><p><a href="/products/apm">Elastic APM</a> gives you rich insights into your application performance and visibility for distributed workloads. This data paired with infrastructure metrics&nbsp;and logs allows you to troubleshoot faster and observe the whole picture as you move your apps to production. Elastic APM supports languages such as Java, Go, Ruby, Python, .NET, and Javascript and even has integrations to standards such as OpenTracing and OpenTelemetry that are popular in the Cloud Native landscape.
</p><p>With ECK 0.9.0 you can now add all this functionality with Elastic APM Server as a new manageable custom resource alongside Elasticsearch and Kibana. To learn more about spinning up Elastic APM Server with ECK, visit <a href="/guide/en/cloud-on-k8s/0.9/k8s-apm-server.html">our quickstart guide</a>.
</p><h2>Custom plugins, bundles, Docker repositories, and config</h2><p>One of the new features in ECK 0.9.0 is enhancements to the Elasticsearch and Kibana custom resources. These enhancements include support for adding custom plugins, bundles, and custom configuration for both Kibana and Elastic APM Server. Users who are running Kubernetes in an air-gapped environment or want to use a custom Docker repository can use the new pod template options to specify a Docker repository including credentials.
</p><h2>More security your way</h2><p>ECK comes with free security on by default for every deployment created. We also understand customers may make use of custom HTTP certificates when accessing Elasticsearch and Kibana. We’ve now extended the custom resources to accept custom HTTP certificates when creating new deployments. In addition, users can leverage ECK 0.9.0 customization options to add authentication such as SAML and OpenID.
</p><h2>Conclusion</h2><p>Be sure to check the release notes for even more details on changes in version 0.9.0. <a href="/elasticsearch-kubernetes">Download ECK 0.9.0 to get started</a>, and we look forward to your feedback.
</p>]]></description><link>https://www.elastic.co/blog/announcing-elastic-cloud-on-kubernetes-eck-0-9-0-alpha-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.elastic.co/blog/announcing-elastic-cloud-on-kubernetes-eck-0-9-0-alpha-2</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Anurag Gupta]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>